<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Faculty on 연세대학교 대기과학과</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/teams/faculty/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Faculty on 연세대학교 대기과학과</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>ko</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 13:39:46 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/teams/faculty/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>전혜영</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/people/hyeyeongchun/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 11:39:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/people/hyeyeongchun/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;연구분야&#34;&gt;연구분야&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;대기중력파&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;중규모기상학&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;중층대기역학&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;항공난류&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;학력&#34;&gt;학력&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ph.D.&lt;/strong&gt; (1991) in Atmospheric Sciences, North Carolina State University, USA&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;M.Sc&lt;/strong&gt; (1987) in Meteorology, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B.Sc&lt;/strong&gt; (1985) in Meteorology, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;담당과목&#34;&gt;담당과목&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;대기역학 I, II&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;고급대기역학&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;중층대기특론&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;중규모기상학&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;약력&#34;&gt;약력&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2010 ~ : 한국 과학기술한림원 이학부 정회원&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1996 ~ : 연세대학교 대기과학과 조교수/부교수/정교수&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2020 - 2021: 한국기상학회 회장&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2019 - 2021: 국가기후환경회의 국제협력분과 전문위원&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2016 - 2018: 연세대학교 학부대학 학장&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2015 - 2017: 국가지속가능발전위원회 위원&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2013 - 2015: BK21+ 지구대기천문사업단 단장&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2011 - 2019: International Commission of the Middle Atmosphere&#xA;(ICMA/IAMAS/IUFF) 위원&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2011 : 독일 JRC 방문교수&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2010 : 미국 JPL/NASA 방문학자&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2004 : 일본 교토대학 방문교수&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2003 : 미국 ATDD/ARL/NOAA 방문학자&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1995 - 1996 : 연세대학교 지구환경연구소 연구원&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1993 - 1995 : 서울대학교 자연과학연구소 특별연구원&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1992 - 1993 : 미국 GSFC/NASA 연구원&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;최근-5년간-논문2017-2022&#34;&gt;최근 5년간 논문(2017-2022)&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Shin, Y. J.-H. Kim, &lt;strong&gt;H.-Y. Chun&lt;/strong&gt;, W. Jang, and S.-W. Son, 2022: Classification of synoptic patterns with mesoscale mechanisms for downslope windstorms in Korea using the self-organizing map. &lt;em&gt;J. Geophys. Res. Atmos.&lt;/em&gt; (accepted)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>염성수</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/people/seongsooyum/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/people/seongsooyum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;연구분야&#34;&gt;연구분야&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;구름물리학&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;구름관측 및 수치모형연구&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;학력&#34;&gt;학력&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ph.D.&lt;/strong&gt; (1998) Univ. of Nevada, Reno, USA&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;M.Sc.&lt;/strong&gt; (1986) Dep. of Astronomy &amp;amp; Atmospheric Science, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B.Sc.&lt;/strong&gt; (1984) Dep. of Astronomy &amp;amp; Meteorology, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;연구경력&#34;&gt;연구경력&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yale University in U.S.A (Post Doc. 2001.3-2001.8)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Desert Research Institute in U.S.A (Post Doc. 1998.9-2001.3)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Metri in KMA, Lab. of App. &amp;amp; Radar (기상연구사,1987.8- 1990.6)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;담당과목&#34;&gt;담당과목&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;대기물리&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;기상통계분석&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;구름 및 강수과정&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;기상자료처리법&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;논문&#34;&gt;논문&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, A. H., Yum, S. S., Chang, D. Y., &amp;amp; Park, M. (2020). Optimization of Sulfate Aerosol Hygroscopicity Parameter in WRF-Chem version (3.8.1). Geoscientific Model Development Discussions, 1-27.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chang, D. Y., J. Lelieveld, B. Steil, J. Yoon, S. S. Yum, and A.-H. Kim, 2020: Variability of aerosol-cloud interactions induced by different cloud droplet nucleation schemes. Atmos. Res., accepted.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;김민석, 이서영, 조예슬, 구자호, 염성수, 김준, 2020: 서울의 기상 조건에 따른 미세먼지와 시정 거리의 상관성, 대기, 게재 승인&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, N., S. S. Yum, M. Park, J. S. Park, H. J. Shin, and J. Y. Ahn, 2020: Hygroscopicity of urban aerosols and its link to size-resolved chemical composition during spring/summer in Seoul, Korea. Atmos. Chem. Phys., 20, 11245-11262, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-20-11245-2020&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-20-11245-2020&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Choi, K. O., S. S. Yum, D. Y. Chang, J. M. Yeom and S. S. Lee, 2020: A study of the effect of regenerated CCN on marine stratocumulus cloud development using the WRF-LES model with spectral bin microphysics scheme. Atmos. Res., 246,  &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.atomsres.2020.105100&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.atomsres.2020.105100&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cha, J. W., and S. S. Yum, 2020: Characteristics of precipitation particles measured by PARSIVEL disdrometer at a mountain and a coastal site in Korea. Asia-Pac. J. Atmos. Sci., &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s13143-020-00190-6&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s13143-020-00190-6&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Park, M., S. S. Yum, N. Kim, B. E. Anderson, A. Beyersdorf, and K. L. Thornhill, 2020: On the submicron aerosol distributions and CCN activity in and around the Korean Peninsula measured onboard the NASA DC-8 research aircraft during the KORUS-AQ campaign, Atmos. Res., 243, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.atmosres.2020.105004&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.atmosres.2020.105004&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lu, C., Y. Liu, S. S. Yum, J. Chen, L. Zhu, S. Gao, Y. Yin, X. Jia, and Y. Wang, 2020: Reconciling contrasting relationships between relative dispersion and volume-mean radius of cloud droplet size distributions. J. Geophys. Res., 125, e2019JD031868, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2019JD031868&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2019JD031868&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Zhu, L, C. Lu, S. Gao and S. S. Yum, 2020: Spectral width of cloud droplet spectra and its impact factors in marine stratocumulus. Chinese J. of Atmos. Sci., 44, 575-590, doi: 10.3878/j.issn.1006-9895.1905.19115.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Park, J., M. Dall’Ssto, K. Park. Y. Gim, H. J. Kang, E. Jang, K.-T. Park, M. Park, S. S. Yum, J. Jung, B. Y. Lee, and Y. J. Yoon, 2020: Shipborne observations reveal contrasting Arctic marine, Arctic terrestrial and Pacific marine aerosol properties. Atmos. Chem. Phys., 20, 5573-5590, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-20-5573-2020&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-20-5573-2020&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, W., S. S. Yum, J. Hong, and J. I. Song, 2020: Improvement of fog predictability by the nudging of a meteorological tower data in the WRF and PAFOG coupled model. Atmosphere, 11, 311, doi:10.3390/atmos11030311.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;La, I., S. S. Yum, I. Gultepe, J. M. Yeom, J. I. Song, and J. W. Cha, 2020: Influence of quasi-periodic oscillation of atmospheric variables on radiation fog over a mountainous region of Korea. Atmosphere, 11, 230, doi:10.3390/atmos11030230.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, W., S. S. Yum, and C. K. Kim, 2020: Numerical simulation of sea fog over the Yellow Sea: Comparison between UM+PAFOG and WRF+PAFOG coupled systems. Asia-Pac. J. of Atmos. Sci., 56, 89-105, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s13143-019-00134-9&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s13143-019-00134-9&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Min, S., K.-H. Shin, W. Baek, K. Kim, C.-H. You, D.-I. Lee, S. S. Yum, W. Kim, K.-H. Chang, 2020: Dynamical Behavior of Combined Detrended Cross-Correlation Analysis Methods in Random Walks and Levy Flights. Physica A: Stat. Mech. And Appl., 539, 122872, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physa.2019.122872&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physa.2019.122872&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;송재인, 염성수, 2019: 서울에서의 미세먼지 저감을 위한 인공강수 가능성 진단. 대기, 29, 609-614, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.14191/Atmos.2019.29.5.609&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.14191/Atmos.2019.29.5.609&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;심성보, 권상훈, 임윤진, 염성수, 변영화, 2019: 1.5/2.0 C 지구온난화 시나리오 기반의 동아시아 기후변화 분석. 대기, 29, 391-401, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.14191/Atmos.2019.29.4.391&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.14191/Atmos.2019.29.4.391&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Shim, S., J. Kim, S. S. Yum, H. Lee, K.-O. Boo and Y.-W. Byun, 2019: Effects of anthropogenic and natural forcings on the summer temperature variations in East Asia during the 20th century. Atmosphere, 10, 690, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos10110690&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos10110690&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yeom, J. M., S. S. Yum, F. Mei, B. Schmid, J. Comstock, L. A. Machado, and M. A. Cecchini, 2019: Impact of secondary droplet activation on the contrasting cloud microphysical relationships during the wet and dry seasons in the Amazon. Atmos. Res., 230, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.atmosres.2019.104648&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.atmosres.2019.104648&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Park, J., M. Dall’Osto, K. Park,…..S. S. Yum et al., 2019: Arctic primary aerosol production strongly influenced by reverine organic matter. Environ. Sci. Technol., 53, 8621-8630. DOI: 10.1021/acs.est.9b03399.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yoon, J., D. Y. Chang, J. Lelieveld, A. Pozzer, J. Kim and S. S. Yum, 2019: Empirical evidence of a positive climate forcing of aerosols at elevated albedo. Atmos. Res., 229, 269-279, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.atmosres.2019.07.001&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.atmosres.2019.07.001&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Song, J. I., S. S. Yum, I. Gultepe, K.-H. Chang, and B.-G. Kim, 2019: Development of a new visibility parameterization based on the measurement of fog microphysics at a mountain site in Korea. Atmos. Res., 229, 115-126, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.atmosres.2019.06.011&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.atmosres.2019.06.011&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, C. K, S. S. Yum, H.-G. Kim, and Y.-H. Kang, 2019: A WRF modeling study on the effect of land use changes on fog off the west coast of the Korean peninsula.  Pure. Appl. Geophys., 176, 463-4640,  &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s00024-019-02242-z&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s00024-019-02242-z&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Shin, K.-H., W. Baek, K. Kim, C.-H. You, K.-H. Chang, D.-I. Lee and S. S. Yum, 2019: Neural network and regression methods for optimizations between two meteorological factors. Physica A: Stat. Mech. And Appl., 523, 778-796, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/J.Physa.2019.01.113&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/J.Physa.2019.01.113&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Gultepe, I., … S. S. Yum et al., 2019: A review of high impact weather for aviation meteorology. Pure Appl. Geophys., 176, 1869-1921, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s00023-019-02168-6&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s00023-019-02168-6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Park, M., S. S. Yum, N. Kim, J. W. Cha, B. Shin, S. B. Ryoo, 2018: Characterization of submicron aerosols and CCN measured over the Yellow sea onboard the Gisang 1 research vessel using the positive matrix factorization analysis method. Atmos. Res., 214, 430-441.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Um, J., G. M. McFarquhar, J. L. Stith, C. H. Jung, S. S. lee, J. Y. Lee, Y. Shin, Y. G. Lee, Y. I. Yang, S. S. Yum, B.-G. Kim, J. W. Cha, and A-Reum Ko, 2018: Microphysical characteristics of frozen droplet aggregates from deep convective clouds. Atmos. Phys. Chem., 18, 16915-16930.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, A-H, S. S. Yum, H. Lee, D. Y. Chang, and S. Shim, 2018: Polar cooling effect due to increases of phytoplankton and dimethyl-sulfide emission. Atmosphere, 9, 384, doi:10.3390/atmos9100384&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;김아현, 염성수, 장동영, 2018: 구름방울 활성화 과정 모수화 방법에 따른 구름 형성의 민감도 실험. 대기, 28, 211-222.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, N., M. Park, S. S. Yum, J. S. Park, H. J. Shin, and J. Y. Ahn, 2018: Impact of urban aerosol properties on cloud condensation nuclei (CCN) activity during the KORUS-AQ field campaign. Atmos. Env., 185, 221-236.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lee, S. S., B.-G. Kim, H.-G. Nam, S. S. Yum, Y.-S. Choi, C.-H. Jung, 2018: Factors that control heavy snowfalls in the eastern coast of Korea. Terr. Atmos. Oceanic Sci., 29, 187-200.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lu, C., Y. Liu, B. Zhu, S. S. Yum, S. Krueger, Y. Qiu, S. Niu, and S. Luo, 2018: On which microphysical time scale to use in study of entrainment-mixing mechanisms in clouds. J. Geophys. Res., 123, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/2017JD027985&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/2017JD027985&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Schmale, J., S. Henning, … M. Park, …. S. S. Yum et al., 2018: Long term cloud condensation nuclei number concentration, particle number size distribution, and chemical composition measurements at regionally representative observatories. Atmos. Chem. Phys. 18, 2853-2881, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-18-2853-2018&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-18-2853-2018&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chae, S., K.-H. Chang, S.-K. Seo, J.-Y. Jeong, B.-J. Kim, C.-K. Kim, S. S. Yum, and J. Kim, 2018: Numerical simulations of airborne glaciogenic cloud seeding using the WRF model with the modified Morrison scheme over the Pyeongchang region in the winter of 2016. Adv. Meteor., Vol. 2018, Article ID8453460, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1155/2018/8453460&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1155/2018/8453460&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yeom, J. M., S. S. Yum, Y. Liu and C. Lu, 2017: A study on the entrainment and mixing process in the continental stratocumulus clouds measured during the RACORO campaign. Atmos. Res., 194, 89-99, dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.atmosres.2017.04.028.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Schmale, J., S. Henning, … M. Park, …. S. S. Yum et al., 2017: Collocated observations of cloud condensation nuclei, particle size distributions, and chemical composition. Sci. Data 4:170003 DOI:10.1038/sdata.2017.3.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lee, S. S., B-G Kim, S. S. Yum, K-H Seo, C-H Jung, J. S. Um, Z Li, J. Hong, K-H Chang, 2017: Effects of aerosol on evaporation, freezing and precipitation in a multiple cloud system. Clim Dyn., 48, 1069-1087.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, N., Park, M., Yum, S. S., Park, J. S., Song, I. H., Shin, H. J., … &amp;amp; Lee, G. (2017). Hygroscopic properties of urban aerosols and their cloud condensation nuclei activities measured in Seoul during the MAPS-Seoul campaign. Atmospheric Environment, 153, 217-232.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lee, H., Yum, S. S., &amp;amp; Shim, S. (2016). Implementation of a new empirical relationship between aerosol and cloud droplet concentrations in a climate model. Climate Research, 70(1), 57-76.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Seong Soo Yum, Jian Wang, Yangang Liu, Gunnar Senum, Stephen Springston, Robert McGraw, and Jae Min Yeom, 2015: Cloud microphysical relationships and their implication on entrainment and mixing mechanism for the stratocumulus clouds measured during the VOCALS project, Journal of Geophysical Research, 120,  10.1002/2014JD022802&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Minsu Park, Seong Soo Yum, Jong Hwan Kim, 2015: Characteristics of submicron aerosol number size distribution and new particle formation events measured in Seoul, Korea, during 2004-2012, Asia-Pac. J. Atmos. Sci., 51(1), 1-10&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, J. H., S. S. Yum, S. Shim, W. J. Kim, M. Park, J.-H. Kim, M.-H. Kim, S.-C. Yoon, 2014: On the submicron aerosol distributions and CCN number concentrations in and around the Korean Peninsula, Atmos. Chem. Phys., 14, 8763-8779&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lee, H., S. S. Yum, and S. S. Lee, 2014: A modeling study of the aerosol effects on ice microphysics in convective cloud and precipitation development under different thermodynamic conditions, Atmos. Res., 145-146, 112–129.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, C. K. and S. S. Yum, 2013: A study on the transition mechanism of stratus cloud in fog over warm sea surface using a single column model coupled with WRF, Asia-Pacific Journal of Atmospheric Sciences, 49,  245-257.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;이한아, 염성수, 심성보, 부경온, 조천호 2013: 기상청 지구시스템 모델에서의 구름입자 수농도 모수화방법 개선, 한국기상학회, 대기,  24(1), 111-122.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;송윤영, 염성수 2013: 인천국제공항의 안개 특성에 따른 안개 안정 지수 FSI(Fog Stability Index) 개발 및 검증 , 한국기상학회, 대기 23(4), 2013.12, 443-452&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Song, K. and S. S. Yum, 2012: Anthropogenic radiative forcing of marine stratocumulus clouds under different thermodynamic conditions-an LES model study, Atmos. Res., 118, 370–389&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, C. K., and S. S. Yum, 2012: A numerical study of sea fog formation over cold sea surface using a one-dimensional turbulence model coupled with the Weather Research and Forecasting Model, Boundary Layer Meteorology, 143, 481-505, DOI 10.1007/s10546-012-9706-9 ( 5월).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, C. K., and S. S. Yum, 2012: Marine boundary layer structure for the sea fog formation off the west coast of the Korean Peninsula, Pure and Appl. Geophys., 169, 1121-1135, DOI 10.1007/s00024-011-0325-z ( 5월).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;이한아, 염성수, 2012: Takahashi 구름모형에서의 얼음입자 충돌효율 개선, 대기, 22(1), 73-85.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;김종환,박민수, 심성보, 염성수, 2011: 대관령과 영종도에서 측정한 에어러솔 크기분포 및 CCN 수농도에 관한 연구,대기, 22(1), 87-96.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;K. Kim, S. S. Yum, 2011: A numerical study of sea fog formation over cold sea surface using a one-dimensional, Boundary- Layer Meteorology.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chunsong  Lu, Yangang Liu, Seong Soo Yum, Shengjie Niu, and Satoshi Endo, 2011: A New Approach for Estimating Entrainment Rate in Cumulus Clouds, Geophysical Research Letters.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I. Kleinman, P. H. Daum, Y.-N. Lee, E. R. Lewis, A. J. Sedlacek Ⅲ, G. I. Senum, S. R. Springston, J. Wang, J. Hubbe, J. Jayne, Q. Min, S. S. Yum, and G. Allen, Aerosol concentration and size distribution measured below, in, and above cloud from the DOE G-1 during VOCALS-Rex, Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics, 12, 207-223.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chang  Ki  Kim, Seong Soo Yum, 2011: Marine Boundary Layer Structure for Sea Fog Formation off the West Coast  of the Korean peninsula, Pure And Applied Geophysics.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, J. H., S. S. Yum, S. Shim, S.-C. Yoon, J. G. Hudson, and S.-J. Lee, 2011: On aerosol hygroscopicity, cloud condensation nuclei (CCN) spectra and critical supersaturation measured at two remote islands of Korea between 2006 and 2009, Atmos. Chem. Phys., 11, 12627-12645.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lim, K.-S. S., S.-Y. Hong, S. S. Yum, J. Dudhia, and J. B. Klemp, 2010: Aerosol effects on the development of a supercell storm in a double-moment bulk-cloud microphysics scheme, J. Geophys. Res., 116,D02204, DOI: 10.1029/2010JD014128.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yum, S. S., and J.-W. Cha, 2010: Suppression of very low intensity precipitation in Korea, Atmos. Res., 98, 118-124 (9월).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;이현혜, 김진영, 이승복, 배귀남, 염성수, 2010: 서울 지역 겨울철 대기 에어로졸의 수 농도 및 산란계수 분석, Particle and aerosol research (한국입자에어로졸학회지), 6, 91-103.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Song, M., M. Lee, J. H. Kim, S. S. Yum, G. Lee, and K.-R. Kim, 2010: New particle formation and growth in relation to vertical mixing and chemical species during ABC-EAREX2005. Atmos. Res. 97, 359-370 (7월).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, C. K., and S. S. Yum, 2010: Local meteorological and synoptic characteristics of the fogs formed over Incheon International Airport in the west coast of Korea. Adv. Atmos. Sci., 27, 761-776. (7월)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Wang, J., P. H. Daum, S. S. Yum, Y. Liu, G. I. Senum, M.-L. Lu, J. H. Seinfeld, and H. Jonsson, 2009: Observations of marine stratocumulus microphysics and implications for processes controlling droplet spectra: result from the Marine Stratus/Stratocumulus Experiment (MASE). J. Geophys. Res., 114, D18210, doi:10.1029/2008JD011035 (9월).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, J. H., S. S. Yum, Y.-G. Lee, and B.-C. Choi, 2009: Ship measurements of submicron aerosol size distributions over the Yellow Sea and the East China Sea. Atmos. Res., 93, 700-714. (6월)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lee, M.-J., K.-H. Chang, G.-M. Park, J.-Y. Jeong, H.-Y. Yang, K.-D. Jeong, J.-W. Cha, S. S. Yum, J.-C. Nam, K. Kim and B.-C. Choi, 2009: Preliminary results of the ground-based orographic snow enhancement experiment of the easterly cold fog (cloud) at Daegwallyeong during the 2006 Winter. Adv. Atmos. Sci., 26, 222-228. (3월)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cha, J. W. K.-H. Chang, S. S. Yum and Y.-J. Choi, 2009: Comparison of the bright band characteristics measured by micro rain radar (MRR) at a mountain and a coastal site in South Korea. Adv. Atmos. Sci., 26, 211-221. (3월)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;심성보, 윤영준, 염성수, 차주완, 김종환, 김준, 이방용, 2008: 네펠로미터로 관측한 서울의 에어러솔 산란계수 특성. 대기, 18, 459-474.  (12월)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kuwata, M., Y. Kondo, Y. Miyazaki, J. H. Kim, S. S. Yum, H. Tanimoto, and H. Matsueda, 2008: Cloud condensation nuclei activity at Jeju Island, Korea in spring 2005. Atmos. Chem. Phys., 8, 2933-2948. (6월?)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Liu, Y., P. Daum, and S. S. Yum, 2008: Ship tracks revisited: new understanding and cloud parameterization. Asia-Pacific Journal of Atmospheric Sciences, 44, 1-9. (1월)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yang, H.-J., and S. S. Yum, 2007: Effects of Prescribed Initial Cloud Droplet Spectra on Convective Cloud and Precipitation Developments under Different Thermodynamic Conditions: a Modeling and Observational Study. Atmos. Res., 86, 207-224.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;이승철, 김종환, 염성수, 조천호 안강호, 2007: H-TDMA를 이용한 대기 에어로졸 흡습성 측정. Particle and Aerosol Research, 3권, 3-4호, 95-103. (11월)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yum, S. S., G. Roberts, J. H. Kim , K. Song and D. Kim, 2007: Submicron aerosol size distributions and cloud condensation nuclei concentrations measured at Gosan, Korea during the ABC-EAREX 2005. J. Geophys. Res., 112, D22S32, doi:10.1029/2006JD008212.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;장기호, 오성남, 정기덕, 양하영, 이명주, 정진임, 조요한, 김효경, 박균명, 염성수, 차주완, 2007: 구름물리관측시스템 및 산출물검정. 대기, 17, 101-108.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cha, J. W., S. S. Yum, K.-H. Chang, and S. N. Oh, 2007: Estimation of the Melting Layer from a Micro Rain Radar (MRR) data at the Cloud Physics Observation System (CPOS) site at Daegwallyeong Weather Station. J. the Korean Meteor. Soc., 43, 1, 77-85.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lee, Y., B. Choi and S. S. Yum, 2006: Characteristics of atmospheric aerosols observed at Anmyeon, Korea during the ABC Gosan EAREX 2005 campaign period. International Journal of Applied Environmental Sciences, 1, 1.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Liu, Y., P. Daum, and S. S. Yum, 2006: Analytical expression for the relative dispersion of the cloud droplet size distribution. Geophys. Res. Lett., 33, L02810, doi:10.1029/2005GL024052.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;김창기, 염성수, 오성남, 남재철, 장기호, 2005: 한반도에서의 인공증우(설) 실험 성공 가능성에 대한 연구. 한국기상학회지, 41, 997-1014.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yum, S. S., J. G. Hudson, K. Y. Song, and B. Choi, 2005: Springtime cloud condensation nuclei concentrations on the west coast of the Korea. Geophy. Res. Lett., 32, L09814, doi:10.1029/2005GL022641.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yum, S. S., and J. G. Hudson, 2005: Adiabatic predictions and observations of cloud droplet spectral broadness. Atmos. Res., 73, 203-223.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;염성수, 오성남, 김정윤, 김창기, 남재철, 2004: 전방산란 스펙트로미터(FSSP)를 이용한 구름입자 크기분포 관측. 한국기상학회지, 40, 623-631.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;염성수, 2004: 작은 온난 적운에서의 구름미세물리 상관관계의 규모 의존성. 한국기상학회지, 40, 531-540.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;양희정 과 염성수, 2004: 2차원 구름모형을 이용한 인공증우 실험 연구. 한국기상학회지, 40, 419-439.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;송근용 과 염성수, 2004: ACE Asia 기간 중 해양성/대륙성 구름의 미세물리적 대조에 대한 연구. 한국기상학회지, 40, 147-159.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yum, S. S., and J. G. Hudson, 2004: Wintertime/summertime contrasts of cloud condensation nuclei and cloud microphysics over the Southern Ocean. J. Geophys. Res., 109, D06204, doi:10.1029/2003JD003864. (3월 27일)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hudson, J. G., and S. S. Yum, 2002: Cloud condensation nuclei spectra and polluted and clean clouds over the Indian Ocean. J. Geophys. Res., 107, D19, 8022, doi:10.1029/2001JD000829.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yum, S. S., and J. G. Hudson, 2002: Maritime/continental microphysical contrasts in stratocumulus. Tellus, Series B, 54, 61-73.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Twohy, C. H., J. G. Hudson, J. R. Anderson, S. K. Durlak, S. S. Yum, and D. Baumgardner, 2001: Characteristics of Cloud Nucleating Aerosols in the Indian Ocean Region. J. Geophys. Res., 106,   28699- 28710.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yum, S. S., and J. G. Hudson, 2001: Vertical distributions of cloud condensation nuclei spectra over the springtime Arctic Ocean. J. Geophys. Res, 106, 15045-15052.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hudson, J. G., and S. S. Yum, 2001: Marine-continental drizzle contrast in small cumuli. J. Atmos. Sci., 58, 915-926.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yum, S. S., and J. G. Hudson, 2001: Microphysical relationships in warm clouds. Atmos. Res., 57, 81-104.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hudson, J. G., T. J. Garrett, P. V. Hobbs, S. R. Strader, Y. Xie, and S. S. Yum, 2000: Cloud condensation nuclei and ship track clouds. J. Atmos. Sci., 57, 2696-2706.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hudson, J. G., and S. S. Yum, 1999: Reply to comments on “Droplet spectral broadening in marine stratus” by Telford. J. Atmos. Sci., 56, 2264-2265.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hudson, J. G., Y. Xie and S. S. Yum, 1998: Vertical distribution of cloud condensation nuclei spectra over the summertime Southern Ocean. J. Geophys. Res., 103, 16609-16624.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yum, S. S., J. G. Hudson, and Y. Xie, 1998: Comparisons of cloud microphysics with cloud condensation nuclei spectra over the summertime Southern Ocean. J. Geophys. Res., 103, 16625-16636.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hudson, J. G., and S. S. Yum, 1997: Droplet spectral broadening in marine stratus. J. Atmos. Sci., 54, 2642-2654.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>김준</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/people/jhoonkim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/people/jhoonkim/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;연구분야&#34;&gt;연구분야&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;대기복사&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;대기환경, 기후변화&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;위성원격탐사&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;에어러솔 및 미량기체 원격측정 및 분석&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;학력&#34;&gt;학력&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ph.D.&lt;/strong&gt; (1991) 미시건대학교 (앤아버), 공과대학 대기.우주과학&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;M.S.&lt;/strong&gt; (1987)  미시건대학교 (앤아버), 공과대학 대기과학&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B.S.&lt;/strong&gt; (1986)  서울대학교 자연과학대학 대기과학&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;경력&#34;&gt;경력&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2003 - 현재     : 연세대학교 대기과학과/지구환경연구소 교수, 연세 이윤재 펠로우&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1991 - 2003    : 한국항공우주연구원(KARI) 책임연구원, 선임연구원&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2021 - 현재     : 한국과학기술한림원 이학부 정회원&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2021 - 2022    : SAIT(삼성종합기술원) 미세먼지연구소장 겸 탄소포집연구소장&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2017 - 2020    : International Radiation Commission (IRC) 위원&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2017 - 2024    : WMO (세계기상기구) GAW Urban Research Meteorology and Environment (GURME) 과학자문위원&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2016 - 2017    : Harvard | Smithonian Center, Atmospheric Measurement Group 방문과학자&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2014 - 2017    : WHO (세계보건기구) Global Platform for Air Quality and Health, 자문위원&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2012 - 현재     : 환경위성탑재체알고리즘개발 연구단장, GEMS (Geostationary Environment Monitoring Spectrometer) Mission&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2012 - 2020    : International Ozone Commission (IO3C) 위원&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2010 - 현재     : CEOS (Committee on Earth Observing Satellites) AC-VC 위원&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2009 - 2010    : NASA Jet Propulsion Laboratory/CalTech 과학기술고문, 미국 UCLA 객원학자&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;수상&#34;&gt;수상&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2024&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;9        :        미국 미시건 대학 공과대학 Alumni Merit Award&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2020, 2019, 2013, 2012 :        연세대학교 우수강의 교수상&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2019&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;4        :        정부 과학기술 포장&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2018&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2        :        과학기술정보통신부 한국연구재단,  이달의 과학기술인&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2018&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1        :        연세대학교 공헌교수상&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2017&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;6        :        NASA Group Achievement Award&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;담당-과목&#34;&gt;담당 과목&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;대기환경&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;대기물리2&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;대기복사론&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;환경원격탐사&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;논문&#34;&gt;논문&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, J., and Coauthors, 2020: New Era of Air Quality Monitoring from Space: Geostationary Environment Monitoring Spectrometer (GEMS). BAMS, 101, E1–E22, https://doi.org/10.1175/BAMS-D-18-0013.1.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, J., M. Kim, and M. Choi (2017), Monitoring Aerosol Properties in East Asia from Geostationary Orbit: GOCI, MI and GEMS, ‘Air Pollution in Eastern Asia: An Integrated Perspective’, Chapter 15, 323-334, ISSI Scientific Report Ser. Vol. 16, edited by Idir Bouarar, Xuemei Wang, and Guy Brasseur, Springer, 504pp, ISBN:978-3-319-59488-0, DOI: 10.1007/978-3-319-59489-7&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Choi, M.J., Jhoon Kim, Jaehwa Lee, Mijin Kim, Young-Je Park, Brent Holben, Thomas F. Eck, Zhengqiang Li, Chul H. Song (2018), GOCI Yonsei aerosol retrieval version 2 aerosol products: improved algorithm description and error analysis with uncertainty estimation from 5-year validation over East Asia, Atmospheric Measurement Technique, 11, 385-408 10.5194/amt-11-385-2018&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jeong, Ukkyo, Jhoon Kim, Hanlim Lee, Yun Gon Lee (2017), Assessing the effect of long-range pollutant transport on air quality in Seoul using the conditional potential source contribution function method, Atmospheric Environment, 150, 33-44, doi: 10.1016/j.atmosenv.2016.11.017.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, J., J. Lee, H.C. Lee, A. Higurashi, T. Takemura, and C.H. Song (2007), Consistency of the aerosol type classification from satellite remote sensing during the ABC EAREX campaign, J. Geophys. Res., 112, D22S33, doi:10.1029/2006JD008201&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, J., C.J. Park, K.Y. Lee, D.H. Lee, Y.O. Kim, H.K. Cho, G.R. Cho, and J. H. Park (1997), Rocket soundings of ozone profiles in the stratosphere over the Korean Peninsula, J. Geophys. Res., 102, 16121.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;외 논문 다수 (&lt;a href=&#34;http://atrad.yonsei.ac.kr/bbs/board.php?tbl=bbs31&#34;&gt;http://atrad.yonsei.ac.kr/bbs/board.php?tbl=bbs31&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>김현미</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/people/hyunmeekim/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/people/hyunmeekim/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;연구분야&#34;&gt;연구분야&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;자료동화, 예측가능성, 확률 예측&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;대기질 모델링, 탄소 인버스 모델링&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;최적관측, 관측망 디자인, 관측영향평가&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;재분석/재예측과 기후 빅데이터&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;종관규모 및 대규모역학&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;학력&#34;&gt;학력&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ph.D.&lt;/strong&gt; (2002) Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences, University of Wisconsin-Madison, USA&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;M.S.&lt;/strong&gt; (1992) Atmospheric Sciences, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B.S.&lt;/strong&gt; (1990) Atmospheric Sciences, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;연구-경력&#34;&gt;연구 경력&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2014-current : Professor, Yonsei University&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2009-2014    : Associate professor, Yonsei University&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2005-2008    : Assistant professor, Yonsei University&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2003-2005    : Research Scientist, Korea Meteorological Administration&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2002-2003    : Research Associate, Dept. of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences, Univ. of Wisconsin-Madison&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1992-1997    : Research Scientist, Korea Meteorological Administration&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;담당과목&#34;&gt;담당과목&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;자료동화&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;대기예측&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;기상재해&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;환경과 대기&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;대기역학 I, 대기역학 II&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;예측가능성론&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;논문&#34;&gt;논문&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, D.-H., and H. M. Kim, 2024: Effect of microphysics scheme and data assimilation on hydrometer and radiative flux simulations in the Arctic. Royal Society Open Science, 11, 240594, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1098/rsos.240594&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1098/rsos.240594&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cho, Y., H. M. Kim, E.-G. Yang, Y. Lee, J.-B. Lee, and S. Ha, 2024: Effect of meteorological data assimilation on regional air quality forecasts over the Korean Peninsula. Journal of Meteorological Research, 38, 1-23. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s13351-024-3152-8&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s13351-024-3152-8&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ha, S., R. Kumar, G. G. Pfister, Y. Lee, D. Lee, H. M. Kim, and Y.-H. Ryu, 2024: Chemical data assimilation with aqueous chemistry in WRF-Chem coupled with WRFDA (V4.4.1). Journal of Advances in Modeling Earth Systems, 16, e2023MS003928, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2023MS003928&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2023MS003928&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Seo, M.-G., H. M. Kim, and D.-H. Kim, 2024: Effect of atmospheric conditions and VPRM parameters on high-resolution regional CO2 simulations over East Asia. Theoretical and Applied Climatology, 155, 859-877, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s00704-023-04663-2&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s00704-023-04663-2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, D.-H., and H. M. Kim, 2024: Design of buoy observation network over the Arctic Ocean. Cold Regions Science and Technology, 218, 104087, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coldregions.2023.104087&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coldregions.2023.104087&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, D.-H., and H. M. Kim, 2023: Evaluation of observation impact on the meteorological forecasts associated with heat wave in 2018 over East Asia using observing system experiments. Heliyon, 9, e23064, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e23064&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e23064&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Seo, M.-G., and H. M. Kim, 2023: Effect of meteorological data assimilation using 3DVAR on high-resolution simulations of atmospheric CO2 concentrations in East Asia. Atmospheric Pollution Research, 14, 101759, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apr.2023.101759&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apr.2023.101759&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Terao T., S. Kanae, H. Fujinami, S. Das, A. P. Dimri, S. Dutta, K. Fujita, A. Fukushima, K.-J. Ha, M. Hirose, J. Hong, H. Kamimera, R. B. Kayastha, M. Kiguchi, K. Kikuchi, H. M. Kim, A. Kitoh, H. Kubota, W. Ma, Y. Ma, M. Mujumdar, M. I. Nodzu, T. Sato, Z. Su, S. Sugimoto, H. G. Takahashi, Y. Takaya, S. Wang, K. Yang, S. Yokoi, and J. Matsumoto, 2023: AsiaPEX: Challenges and Prospects in Asian Precipitation Research. Bulletin of the American Meteorological Society.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, D.-H., and H. M. Kim, 2022: Deep learning for downward longwave radiative flux forecasts in the Arctic. Expert Systems With Applications, 210, 118547, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eswa.2022.118547&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eswa.2022.118547&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yang, E.-G., H. M. Kim, and D.-H. Kim, 2022: Development of East Asia Regional Reanalysis based on advanced hybrid gain data assimilation method and evaluation with E3DVAR, ERA-5, and ERA-Interim reanalysis. Earth System Science Data, 14, 2109-2127, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5194/essd-14-2109-2022&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5194/essd-14-2109-2022&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, D.-H., and H. M. Kim, 2022: Effect of data assimilation in the Polar WRF with 3DVAR on the prediction of radiation, heat flux, cloud, and near surface atmospheric variables over Svalbard. Atmospheric Research, 272, 106155, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.atmosres.2022.106155&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.atmosres.2022.106155&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cho, M., and H. M. Kim, 2022: Effect of assimilating CO2 observations in the Korean Peninsula on the inverse modeling to estimate surface CO2 flux over Asia. PLoS ONE, 17, e0263925. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0263925&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0263925&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, H. M., and D.-H. Kim, 2021: Effect of boundary conditions on adjoint-based forecast sensitivity observation impact in a regional model. Journal of Atmospheric and Oceanic Technology, 38, 1233-1247, doi:10.1175/JTECH-D-20-0040.1.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yang, E.-G., and H. M. Kim, 2021: A comparison of variational, ensemble-based, and hybrid data assimilation methods over East Asia for two one-month periods, Atmospheric Research, 249,105257, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.atmosres.2020.105257&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.atmosres.2020.105257&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Park, J., and H. M. Kim, 2020: Design and evaluation of CO₂ observation network to optimize surface CO₂ fluxes in Asia using observation system simulation experiments, Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics, 20, 5175-5195, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-20-5175-2020&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-20-5175-2020&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, D.-H., H. M. Kim, and J. Hong, 2019: Evaluation of wind forecasts over Svalbard using the high-resolution Polar WRF with 3DVAR, Arctic, Antarctic, and Alpine Research, 51, 471-489, doi:10.1080/ 15230430.2019.1676939.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;He, J., F. Zhang, X. Chen, X. Bao, D. Chen, H. M. Kim, H.-W. Lai, L. R. Leung, X. Ma, Z. Meng, T. Ou, Z. Xiao, E.-G. Yang, and K. Yang, 2019: Development and evaluation of an ensemble-based data assimilation system for regional reanalysis over the Tibetan Plateau and surrounging regions, Journal of Advances in Modeling Earth Systems, 11, 2503-2522, doi:10.1029/2019MS001665.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, S.-M., and H. M. Kim, 2019: Forecast sensitivity observation impact in the 4DVAR and Hybrid-4DVAR data assimilation systems, Journal of Atmospheric and Oceanic Technology, 36, 1563-1575, doi:10.1175/JTECH-D-18-0240.1.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hwang, S.-O., J. Park,and H. M. Kim, 2019: Effect of hydrometeor species on very-short-range simulations of precipitation using ERA5, Atmospheric Research, 218, 245-256, doi:10.1016/j.atmosres.2018.12.008.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On, N., H. M. Kim, and S. Kim, 2018: Effects of resolution, cumulus parameterization scheme, and probability forecasting on precipitation forecasts in a high-resolution limited-area ensemble prediction system, Asia-Pacific Journal of Atmospheric Sciences, 54, 623-637, doi:10.1007/s13143-018-0081-4.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, S.-M., and H. M. Kim, 2018: Effect of observation error variance adjustment on numerical weather prediction using forecast sensitivity to error covariance parameters, Tellus A, 70, 1-16, doi:10.1080 /16000870.2018.1492839&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, D.-H., and H. M. Kim, 2018: Effect of assimilating Himawari-8 atmospheric motion vectors on forecast errors over East Asia, Journal of Atmospheric and Oceanic Technology, 35, 1737-1752, doi:10.1175/JTECH-D-17-0093.1.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, H., H. M. Kim, M. K. Cho, J. Park, and D.-H. Kim, 2018:  Development of the aircraft CO₂ measurement data assimilation system to improve the estimation of surface CO₂ fluxes using an inverse modeling system, Atmosphere, 28(2), 1-9, doi:10.14191/Atmos.2018.28.2.113. (in Korean with English abstract)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Noh, K., H. M. Kim, and D.-H. Kim, 2018: Development of the three-dimensional variational data assimilation system for the Republic of Korea Air Force operational numerical weather prediction system, Journal of the Korea Institute of Military Science and Technology, 21(3), 403-412, doi:10.9766/KIMST.2018.21.3.403. (in Korean with English abstract)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, H., H. M. Kim, J. Kim, and C.-H. Cho, 2018: Effect of data assimilation parameters on the optimized surface CO₂ flux in Asia, Asia-Pacific Journal of Atmospheric Sciences, 54, 1-17, doi:10.1007/s13143-017-0049-9.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yang, E.-G., and H. M. Kim, 2017: Evaluation of a regional reanalysis and ERA-Interim over East Asia using in situ observations during 2013-14, Journal of Applied Meteorology and Climatology, 56, 2821-2844, doi: 10.1175/JAMC-D-16-0227.1.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, S., and H. M. Kim, 2017: Effect of considering sub-grid scale uncertainties on the forecasts of a high-resolution limited area ensemble prediction system, Pure and Applied Geophysics, 174(5), 2021-2037, doi: 10.1007/s00024-017-1513-2.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, S.-M., and H. M. Kim, 2017: Adjoint-based observation impact of Advanced Microwave Sounding Unit-A (AMSU-A) on the short-range forecast in East Asia, Atmosphere, 27(1), 93-104, doi:10.14191/Atmos.2017.27.1.093. (in Korean with English abstract)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, M., H. M. Kim, J. Kim, S.-M. Kim, C. Velden, and B. Hoover, 2017: Effect of enhanced satellite-derived atmospheric motion vectors on numerical weather prediction in East Asia using an adjoint-based observation impact method, Weather and Forecasting, 32, 579-594, doi:10.1175/WAF-D-16-0061.1.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, J., H. M. Kim, C.-H. Cho, K.-O. Boo, A. R. Jacobson, M. Sasakawa, T. Machida, M. Arshinov, and N. Fedoseev, 2017: Impact of Siberian observations on the optimization of surface CO₂flux, Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics, 17, 2881-2899, doi:10.5194/acp-17-2881-2017.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, H. J., H. M. Kim, J. Kim, and C.-H. Cho, 2016: A Comparison of the Atmospheric CO₂ Concentrations Obtained by an Inverse Modeling System and Passenger Aircraft Based Measurement, Atmosphere, 26(3), 387-400. (in Korean with English abstract)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, S., H. M. Kim, J. K. Kay, and S.-W. Lee, 2015: Development and evaluation of high resolution limited area ensemble prediction system in KMA, Atmosphere, 25(1), 67-83. (in Korean with English abstract)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, J., H. M. Kim, and C.-H. Cho, 2014: Influence of CO₂ observations on the optimized CO₂ flux in an ensemble Kalman filter, Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics, 14, 13515-13530, doi:10.5194/acp-14-13515-2014.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yang, E.-G., H. M. Kim, J. Kim, and J. K. Kay, 2014: Effect of observation network design on meteorological forecasts of Asian dust events, Monthly Weather Review, 142, 4679-4695, doi:10.1175/MWR-D-14-00080.1.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, S.-M., and H. M. Kim, 2014: Sampling error of observation impact statistics, Tellus A, 66, 25435, &lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.3402/tellusa.v66.25435&#34;&gt;http://dx.doi.org/10.3402/tellusa.v66.25435&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kay, J. K., and H. M. Kim, 2014: Characteristics of initial perturbations in the ensemble prediction system of the Korea Meteorological Administration, Weather and Forecasting, 29, 563-581, doi: 10.1175/WAF-D-13-00097.1.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, J., H. M. Kim, and C.-H. Cho, 2014: The effect of optimization and the nesting domain on carbon flux analyses in Asia using a carbon tracking system based on the ensemble Kalman filter, Asia-Pacific Journal of Atmospheric Sciences, 50, 327-344, doi:10.1007/s13143-014-0020-y.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jung, B.-J., H. M. Kim, T. Auligne, X. Zhang, X. Zhang, and X.-Y. Huang, 2013: Adjoint-derived observation impact using WRF in the western North Pacific, Monthly Weather Review, 141, 4080-4097.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, H. M., J. K. Kay, E.-G. Yang, S. Kim, M. Lee, 2013: Statistical adjoint sensitivity distributions for meteorological forecast errors of Asian dust transport events in Korea, Tellus B, 65, 20554, &lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10/3402/tellusb.v65i0.20554&#34;&gt;http://dx.doi.org/10/3402/tellusb.v65i0.20554&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kay, J. K., H. M. Kim, Y.-Y. Park, and J. Son, 2013: Effect of doubling ensemble size on the performance of ensemble prediction in warm season using MOGREPS implemented in KMA, Advances in Atmospheric Sciences, 30(5), 1287-1302, doi:10.1007/s00376-012-2083-y.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, S., H. M. Kim, E.-J. Kim, and H.-C. Shin, 2013: Forecast sensitivity to observations for high-impact weather events in the Korean Peninsula, Atmosphere, 23(2), 171-186. (in Korean with English abstract)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Park, S.-Y., H. M. Kim, T.-Y. Lee, and M. Morgan, 2013: Statistical distributions of singular vectors for tropical cyclones affecting Korea over a 10-year period, Meteorology and Atmospheric Physics, 120, 107-122, doi: 10.1007/s00703-013-0247-7.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, J., H. M. Kim, and C.-H. Cho, 2012: Application of Carbon Tracking System based on ensemble Kalman filter on the diagnosis of Carbon Cycle in Asia, Atmosphere, 22(4), 415-427. (in Korean with English abstract)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jung, B.-J., H. M. Kim, F. Zhang, and C.-C. Wu, 2012: Effect of targeted dropsonde observations and best track data on the track forecasts of Typhoon Sinlaku (2008) using an Ensemble Kalman Filter, Tellus A, 64, 14984, doi: 10.3402/tellusa.v64i0.14984.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, H. M., S.-M. Kim, and B.-J. Jung, 2011: Real-time adaptive observation guidance using singular vectors for typhoon Jangmi (200815) in T-PARC 2008, Weather and Forecasting, 26, 634-649, doi: 10.1175/WAF-D-10-05013.1.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, S.-M., H. M. Kim,  S.-W. Joo, H.-C. Shin, and D. Won, 2011: Development of tools for calculating forecast sensitivities to the initial condition in the Korea Meteorological Administration (KMA) Unified Model (UM), Atmosphere, 21(2), 163-172. (in Korean with English abstract)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, H. M., and R. J. Beare, 2011: Characteristics of adjoint sensitivity to potential vorticity. Meteorology and Atmospheric Physics, 111, 91-102, doi: 10.1007/s00703-010-0119-3.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hong, S.-Y., H. M. Kim, J.-E. Kim, S.-O. Hwang, and H. Park, 2011: The impact of model uncertainties on analyzed data in a global data assimilation system, Terrestrial, Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences, 22(1),41-47.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, H. M., and J. K. Kay, 2010: Forecast sensitivity analysis of an Asian dust event occurred on 6-8 May 2007 in Korea, Atmosphere, 20(4), 399-414. (in Korean with English abstract)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Park, J. I., and H. M. Kim, 2010: Typhoon Wukong (200610) prediction based on the Ensemble Kalman Filter and ensemble sensitivity analysis, Atmosphere, 20(3), 287-306. (in Korean with English abstract)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jung, B.-J., H. M. Kim, Y.-H. Kim, E.-H. Jeon, and K.-H. Kim, 2010: Observation system experiments for Typhoon Jangmi (200815) observed during T-PARC, Asia-Pacific J. Atmos. Sci., 46, 305-316.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jung, B.-J. and H. M. Kim, 2009: Moist-adjoint based forecast sensitivities for a heavy snowfall event over the Korean peninsula on 4-5 March 2004, J. Geophys. Res., 114, D15104, DOI:10.1029/2008JD011370.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, H. M., and B.-J. Jung, 2009: Influence of moist physics and norms on singular vectors for a tropical cyclone. Mon. Wea. Rev., 137, 525-543.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, H. M., and B.-J. Jung, 2009: Singular vector structure and evolution of a recurving tropical cyclone. Mon. Wea. Rev., 137, 505-524.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, H. M., B.-J. Jung, Y. -H. Kim, and H.-S. Lee, 2008: Adaptive observation guidance applied to Typhoon Rusa: Implications for THORPEX-PARC 2008. Asia-Pacific J. Atmos. Sci., 44, 297-312.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, H. M., J. K. Kay, and B.-J. Jung, 2008: Application of adjoint-based forecast sensitivities to Asian dust transport events in Korea. Water, Air, and Soil Pollution, 195, 335-343, DOI:10.1007/s11270-008-9750-8.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, H. M., and B.-J. Jung, 2006: Adjoint-based forecast sensitivities of Typhoon Rusa. Geophys. Res. Lett., 33, L21813, DOI:10.1029/2006GL027289.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, H. M., Y. H. Youn, and H. S. Chung, 2004: Potential vorticity thinking as an aid to understanding midlatitude weather systems. Journal of the Korean Meteorological Society, 40(6), 633-647.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, H. M., M. Morgan, and R. E. Morss, 2004: Evolution of analysis error and adjoint-based sensitivities: Implications for adaptive observations.  J. Atmos. Sci., 61, 795-812.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, H. M., 2003: A computation of adjoint-based sensitivities in a quasigeostrophic model.  Korean Journal of the Atmospheric Sciences, 6(2), 71-83.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, H. M. and M. Morgan, 2002: Dependence of singular vector structure and evolution on the choice of norm. J. Atmos. Sci., 59, 3099-3116.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>안순일</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/people/soonilan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/people/soonilan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;연구분야&#34;&gt;연구분야&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;기후역학&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;대기-해양 상호작용&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;El Nino&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;기후변화&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;education&#34;&gt;Education&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ph.D.&lt;/strong&gt; (1996) Atmospheric Sciences, Seoul National University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;M.S.&lt;/strong&gt; (1991) Atmospheric Sciences, Seoul National University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B.S.&lt;/strong&gt; (1989) Atmospheric Sciences, Seoul National University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;scientific-work-experience&#34;&gt;Scientific Work Experience&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Associate Researcher, International Pacific Research Center, SOEST, University of Hawaii, Honolulu, Hawaii, 2002.10~2005.9&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Assistant Researcher, International Pacific Research Center, SOEST, University of Hawaii, Honolulu, Hawaii, 2001.4~2002.9&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Post-Doctoral Fellow, International Pacific Research Center, SOEST, University of Hawaii, Honolulu, Hawaii, 1998.4~2001.3&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Research Associate, Research Institute for Basic Science, Seoul National University, 1996.9~1998.3&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;담당과목&#34;&gt;담당과목&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;기후변화의 이해&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;기후역학&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;해양-대기 상호작용&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;논문&#34;&gt;논문&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;S.-I. An, J. Shin, S.-W. Yeh, S.-W. Son, J.-S. Kug, S.-K., Min, and H.-J. Kim (2021) Global cooling hiatus driven by an AMOC overshoot in a carbon dioxide removal scenario, Earth’s Future&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;J-H Park, M-K Sung, Y-M Yang, J Zhao, S-I An, and J-S Kug, 2021: Role of the climatological intertropical convergence zone in the seasonal footprinting mechanism of the El Niño-Southern Oscillation, Journal of Climate, 34, 5243-5256. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1175/JCLI-D-20-0809.1&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1175/JCLI-D-20-0809.1&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;S-K Kim, and S-I An, 2021: Seasonal gap theory for ENSO phase locking. Journal of Climate, 34, 5621-5634. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1175/JCLI-D-20-0495.1&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1175/JCLI-D-20-0495.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;H-J Kim, S-I An, S-K Kim, and J-H Park, 2021: Feedback processes modulating the sensitivity of Atlantic thermohaline circulation to freshwater forcing timescales. Journal of Climate, 34, 5081-5092, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1175/JCLI-D-20-0897.1&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1175/JCLI-D-20-0897.1&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;E-S Heo, M-K Sung, S-I An, and Y-M Yang, 2021: Decadal phase shift of summertime Arctic dipole pattern and its nonlinear effect on sea ice extent, International Journal of Climatology, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/joc.7097&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/joc.7097&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Y-M Yang, J-H Park, S-I An, B Wang, and X Luo, 2021 : Mean sea surface temperature changes influence ENSO-related precipitation changes in the mid-latitudes. Nature Communications, 12, 1495. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-021-21787-z&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-021-21787-z&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sung, M.-K., S.-W. Son, C. Yoo, J. Hwang, and S.-I. An, 2021: Seesawing of winter extremes between East Asia and North America. Journal of Climate, 1-42. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1175/JCLI-D-20-0789.1&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1175/JCLI-D-20-0789.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;R Olson, S-I An, S-K Kim and Y Fan, 2021 : A novel approach for discovering stochastic models behind data applied to El Niño–Southern Oscillation. Scientific Reports, 11, 2648. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-021-81162-2&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-021-81162-2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;S-I An, H-J Kim, and S-K Kim, 2021: Rate-dependent hysteresis of the Atlantic Meridional Overturning Circulation system and its asymmetric loop. Geophysical Research Letters, 48, e2020GL090132. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2020GL090132&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2020GL090132&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;H-J Kim, S-I An, and D Kim, 2021 : Timescale-dependent AMOC-AMO relationship in an earth system model of intermediate complexity. International Journal of Climatology, 41, E3298-E3306. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/joc.6926&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/joc.6926&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;R Olson, A Timmermann, J-Y Lee, and S-I An, 2021: A low order dynamical model for runoff predictability. Climate Dynamics, 56, 399-422. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s00382-020-05479-w&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s00382-020-05479-w&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;J-H Park, S-I An, J-S Kug, Y-M Yang, T Li, and H-S Jo, 2021 : Mid-latitude leading double-dip La Niña. International Journal of Climatology, 41, E1353-E1370. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/joc.6772&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/joc.6772&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;S-I An, E Tziperman, Y Okumura, and T Li, 2020: Chapter 4: Irregularity and asymmetry. AGU Monograph: ENSO in a Changing Climate.  M. McPhaden, A. Santoso, W. Cai (Eds.), Wiley, published.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;H Kim, S-W Yeh, S-I An, and S-Y Song, 2020 : Changes in the role of Pacific Decadal Oscillation on sea ice extent variability across the mid-1990s. Scientific Reports, 10, 17564. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-020-74260-0&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-020-74260-0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;JR Brown, CM Brierley, S-I An, et al, 2020: Comparison of past and future simulations of ENSO in CMIP5/PMIP3 and CMIP6/PMIP4 models. Climate of the Past, 16, 1777-1805. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5194/cp-2019-155&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5194/cp-2019-155&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;S-Y Jun, J-H Kim, J Choi, S-J Kim, B-M Kim, and S-I An, 2020 : The internal origin of the west-east asymmetry of Antarctic climate change. Science Advances, 6(24), eaaz1490. DOI: 10.1126/sciadv.aaz1490&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;H Kim, S-W Yeh, S-I An, J-H Park, B-M Kim, and E-H Baek, 2020 : Arctic sea ice loss as a potential trigger for central Pacific El Nino events. Geophysical Research letters, 47, e2020GL087028. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2020GL087028&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2020GL087028&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;M-K Sung, C Yoo, S-W Yeh, Y Kosaka, and S-I An, 2020 : Characteristics of the north Pacific Oscillation in CMIP5 models in relation to atmospheric mean states. Journal of Climate, 33, 3809-3825. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1175/JCLI-D-19-0446.1&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1175/JCLI-D-19-0446.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;S-I An, S-K Kim, and A Timmermann, 2020 : Fokker-Planck dynamics of the El Niño-Southern Oscillation. Scientific Reports, 10, 16282. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-020-73449-7&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-020-73449-7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;J Zhao, J-S Kug, J-H Park, and S-I An, 2020: Diversity of North Pacific meridional mode and its distinct impacts on El Niño-Southern Oscillation. Geophysical Research Letters, 47, e2020GL088993. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2020GL088993&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2020GL088993&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Y-M Yang, S-I An, B Wang, and J H Park, 2020: A global-scale multidecadal variability driven by Atlantic multidecadal oscillation. National Science Review, 7, 1190-1197. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1093/nsr/nwz216&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1093/nsr/nwz216&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soong-Ki Kim, Soon-Il An. 2020: Untangling El Niño‐La Niña Asymmetries Using a Nonlinear Coupled Dynamic Index. Geophysical Research Letters, 47, e2019GL085881. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2019GL085881&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2019GL085881&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;J.-H. Park, J.-S. Kug, S.-I. An, and T. Li, 2019: Role of the western hemisphere warm pool in climate variability over the western North Pacific. Climate Dynamics, 53, 2743-2755. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s00382-019-04652-0&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s00382-019-04652-0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;R. Olson, S.-I. An, et al. 2019: A novel method to test non-exclusive hypotheses applied to Arctic ice projections from dependent models. Nature Communications, 10(1), 3016. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-019-10561-x&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-019-10561-x&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jongsoo Shin, Roman Olson, and Soon-Il An. 2019: Improved probabilistic twenty-first century projections of sea surface temperature over East Asian marginal seas by considering uncertainty owing to model error and internal variability. Climate Dynamics, 53, 6075-6087. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s00382-019-04911-0&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s00382-019-04911-0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soon-Il An and Eun Sook Heo. 2019: Robust opposite‐changing tendency between the thermal advection damping by mean current and thermo‐dynamical damping of ENSO Feedback in a changing climate. Royal Meteorological Society. International Journal of Climatology, 39, 5822-5829. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/joc.6176&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/joc.6176&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hyo-Jeong Kim and Soon-Il An. 2019: Impact of North Atlantic Freshwater Forcing on the Pacific Meridional Overturning Circulation under Glacial and Interglacial Conditions. Journal of Climate, 32. 4641-4659. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1175/JCLI-D-19-0065.1&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1175/JCLI-D-19-0065.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Roman Olson, Soon-Il An, Yanan Fan, and Jason P. Evans. 2019: Accounting for skill in trend, variability, and autocorrelation facilitates better multi-model projections: Application to the AMOC and temperature time series. PLoS ONE, 14(4): e021435. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal&lt;/a&gt;. pone.0214535&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;R. Olson, K. L. Ruckert, W. Chang, K. Keller, M. Haran, and S.-I. An, 2018: Stilt: Easy emulation of time series AR(1) computer model output in multidimensional parameter space. The R Journal 10:2, pages 209-225.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ji-Won Kim, and Soon-Il An 2018: Western North Pacific anticyclone chnage associated with the EL Nino-Indian Ocean Dipole coupling. International Journal of Climatology, 39, 2505-2521. &lt;a href=&#34;http://doi.org/10.1002/joc.5967&#34;&gt;http://doi.org/10.1002/joc.5967&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soon-Il An, and Ji-Won Kim 2018: ENSO transition asymmetry: Internal and external causes and intermodel diversity. Geophysical Research Letters, 45, 5095-5104. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2018GL078476&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2018GL078476&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A. Timmermann, and S.-I. An, et al. 2018: El Nino-Southern Oscillation complexity. Nature, 559, 535-545. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-018-0252-6&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-018-0252-6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ji-Won Kim, Soon-Il An. 2018 : Origin of early-spring central Pacific warming as the 1982-1983 El Nino precursor. International Journal of Climatology, 38, 2899-2906. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/joc.5465&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/joc.5465&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soon-Il An. 2018 : Impact of Pacific Decadal Oscillation on Frequency Asymmetry of El Niño and La Niña events. Advances in Atmospheric Sciences, 35, 493-494. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s00376-018-8024-7&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s00376-018-8024-7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soon-Il An, Seul-Hee Im, Sang-Yoon Jun, 2018 : Changes in ENSO activity during the last 6,000 years modulated by background climate state. Geophysical Research Letters, 45, 2467-2475. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/2017GL076250&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/2017GL076250&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sang-Wook Yeh, Wenju Cai, Seung-Ki Min, Michael J. McPhaden, Dietmar Dommenget, Boris Dewitte, Matthew Collins, Karumuri Ashok, Soon-Il An, Bo-Young Yim, Jong-Seong Kug, 2018 : ENSO atmospheric teleconnections and their response to greenhouse gas forcing. Reviews of Geophysics, 56, 185-206. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/2017RG000568&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/2017RG000568&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;So-Jung Shin, Soon-Il An, 2018 :Interdecadal Change in the Relationship Between the North Pacific Oscillation and the Pacific Meridional Mode and Its Impact on ENSO. Asia-Pacific Journal of Atmospheric Sciences, DOI:10.1007/s13143-017-0060-1&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jongsoo Shin, R. Olson, Soon-Il An, 2018 : Projected Heat Wave Characteristics over the Korean Peninsula During the Twenty-First Century. Asia-Pacific Journal of Atmospheric Sciences. DOI:10.1007/s13143-017-0059-7&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;R. Olson,  S. -I. An, Y. Fan, J. P. Evans, L. Caesar, 2017 : North Atlantic observations sharpen meridional overturning projections. Climate Dynamics, doi:10.1007/s00382-017-3867-7.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soon-Il An,  Eun Sook Heo, Seon Tae Kim, 2017 : Feedback process responsible for intermodel diversity of ENSO variability. Geophys. Res. Lett. doi:10.1002/2017GL073203.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soon-Il An,  Hayoung Bong, 2017 : Feedback process responsible for the suppression of ENSO activity during the mid-Holocene. Theor Appl Climatol. doi:10.1007/s00704-017-2117-6.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jae-Heung Park, Soon-Il An, Jong-Seong Kug, 2017 : Interannual variability of western North Pacific SST anomalies and its impact on North Pacific and North America. Cimate Dynamics. doi:10.1007/s00382-017-3538-8.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soon-Il An, Hyo-Jeong Kim,Wonsun Park, Birgit Schneider, 2017 : Impact of ENSO on East Asian winter monsoon during interglacial periods: effect of orbital forcing. Climate Dynamics. doi:10.1007/s00382-016-3506-8.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soon-Il An, Ji-Won Kim, 2017 : Role of nonlinear ocean dynamic response to wind on the asymmetrical transition of El Nino and La Nina. Geophys. Res. Lett., 44, 393-400, doi:10.1002/ 2016GL071971.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ji-Won Kim, Soon-Il An, Sang-Yoon Jun, Hey-Jin Park and Sang-Wook Yeh. 2016 : ENSO and East Asian winter monsoon relationship modulation associated with the anomalous northwest Pacific anticyclone. Climate dynamics. DOI 10.1007/s00382-016-3371-5&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soon-Il An, Hayoung Bong. 2015 : Inter-decadal change in El Nino-Southern Oscillation examined with Bjerknes stability index analysis. Climate dynamics.  DOI 10.1007/s00382-015-2883-8&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Wenju Cai, Agus Santoso, Guojian Wang, Sang-Wook Yeh, Soon-Il An, Kim Cobb, Mat Collins, Guilyardi, Fei-Fei Jin, Jong-Seong Kug, Matthieu Lengaigne, Michael J. McPhaden, Takahashi, Axel Timmermann, Gabriel Vecchi, Masahiro Watanabe and Lixin Wu. 2015 : ENSO and greenhouse warming. Nature climate chage.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Seul-Hee Im, Soon-Il An, Seon Tae Kim, and Fei-Fei Jin. 2015 : Feedback processes responsible for El Nino-La Nina amplitude asymmetry. Geophys. Res. Lett., 42, 5556-5563,&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mi-Kyung Sung, Soon-Il An, Baek-Min Kim, and Jong-Seong Kug. 2015 : Asymmetric impact of Atlantic Multidecadal Oscillation on El Nino and La Nina characteristics. Geophys. Res. Lett., 42, 4998-5004,&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Seung-Ki Min, Seok-Woo Son, Kyong-Hwan Seo, Jong-Seong Kug, Soon-Il An, Yong-Sang Choi, Jee-Hoon Jeong, Baek-Min Kim, Ji-Won Kim, Yeon-Hee Kim, June-Yi Lee, and Myong-In Lee, 2015 : Changes in Weather and climate Extremes over Korea and Possible Causes: A Review. Asia-Pac. J. Atmos. Sci., 51(2), 103-121,&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yu, J.-Y., P.-K. Kao, H. Paek, H.-H. Hsu, C.-W. Hung, M.-M. Lu, and S.-I. An, 2015 : Linking Emergence of the Central-Pacific El Nino to the Atlantic Multi-decadal Oscillation. J.Climate., 28, 651-662.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;S.-I. An., and J. Choi, 2015 : Why the Twenty-first Century Tropical Pacific Trend Pattern cannot significantly influence ENSO Amplitude?. Climate Dynamics., 44, 133-146.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yun Gon Lee, Jhoon Kim,Chang-Hoi Ho ,Soon-Il An, Hi-Ku Cho, Rui Mao, Baijun Tian, Dong Wu, Jae N. Lee,Olga Kalashnikova, Yunsoo Choi and Sang-Wook Yeh.  2014 : The effects of ENSO under negative AO phase on spring dust activity over northern China: an observational investigation. Int. J. Climatol., 35(6). 935-947.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Park, J.-H., and S.-I. An 2014 : Southward displacement of the upper atmosphere zonal jet in the eastern north Pacific due to global warming, Geophysical Res.Lett., 41, 7861-7867(Corresponding author)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, S.-T., W. Cai, F.-F. Jin, A. Santoso, L. Wu, E. Guilyardi, and S.-I. An 2014 : Response of El Nino sea surface temperature variability to greenhouse warming, Nature Climate Change, 4, 786-790.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sung, M.-K., S.-I. An, B.-M. Kim and S.-H. Woo 2014 : A physical mechanism of the precipitation dipole in the western United States based on PDO-storm track relationship. Geophy. Res. Lett., 41, 4719-4726.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ham, Y.-G., M.-K. Sung, S.-I. An, S.D. Schubert and J.-S. Kug 2014 : Role of tropical Atlantic SST variability as a modulator of El Nino teleconnections. Asia-Pacific J. Atmos. Sci., 50(1), 1-15.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Park, J.-H, and S.-I. An 2014 : Impact of Tropical Western Pacific Convection on the North Pacific Atmospheric Circulation during the Boreal Winter. Climate Dynamics,, 43, 2227-2238.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;S.-I. An, and S.-H. Im, 2014 : Blunt ocean dynamical thermostat in response of tropicla eastern Pacific SST to global warming. Theoretical and Applied Climatology,, 118, 173-183.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;S.-I. An, and Choi, 2014 : Mid-Holocene Tropicla Pacific Climate State, Annual Cycle, and ENSO in PMIP2 and PMIP3. Climate Dynamics,, 43, 957-970.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sung, M.-K., Kim, B.-M., S.-I. An, 2014 : Altered atmospheric responses to eastern Pacific and central Pacific El Ninos over the north Atlantic region due to stratospheric interference. Climate Dynamics,, 42, 159-170 (corresponding author)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yeh, S.-W., J.-S. Kug and S.-I. An, 2014 : Recent Progress on Two Types of El Nino : Observations, Dynamics, and Future Changes. Asia Pacific Journal of Atmospheric Sciences, 50(1), 69-81, 2014.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Santos, A., S. McGregor, F.-F. Jin, W. Cai, M.H. England, S.-I. An, M.J. McPhaden and E. Guilyardi, 2013 : Late-twentieth-century emergence of the El Nino propagation asymmetry and future projections. Nature, 504, 126-130.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sung, M. -K., Y.-G. Ham, J.-S. Kug, and S.-I. An, 2013: An Alterative Effect by the Tropical North Atlantic SST  in Intraseasonally Varying El Nino Teleconnection  over the North Atlantic.Tellus A, Tellus A 2013, 65, 19863(corresponding author).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Thual, S., B. Dewitte, S.-I. An, S. Illig, and N. Ayoub, 2013: Influence of Recent Stratification Changes on ENSO stability in a Conceptual Model of the Equatorial Pacific. J. Climate, 26,4790-4802.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;H.-R, Kim. and S.-I. An, 2013: On the Subarctic North Atlantic Cooling due to Global Warming, Theoretical and Applied Climatology, 114, 9-19(corresponding author).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Choi, J., S.-I. An, S.-W. Yeh, and J.-Y. Yu, 2013: ENSO-like and ENSO-induced Tropical Pacific Decadal Variability in CGCMs, J. Climate, 26, 1485-1501(corresponding author).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Park, J.-H., S.-I. An, S.-W. Yeh, and Schneider N., 2013 : Quantitative Assessment of the Climate Components Driving the Pacific Decadal Oscillation in Climate Models, Theor. Appl. Climatol, 112, 431-445(corresponding author).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An, S.-I., H.-R. Kim, and B.-M. Kim, 2013 : Impact of Freshwater Discharge from the Greenland Ice Sheet on North Atlantic Climate Variability, Theor. Appl. Climatol.112,29-43.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An, S.-I. and J.-H. Park, 2013 : Maintenance of PDO Variability during the Mid-­Holocene in PMIP2, Climate Dynamics, 40,1291-1299(Feb 27, 2013).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An, S.-I. and J. Choi, 2013 : Inverse relationship between the equatorial eastern Pacific annual-cycle and ENSO amplitudes in a Coupled General Circulation Model, Climate Dynamics, 40,663-675.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Choi, J. and S.-I. An, 2013 : Quantifying the residual effects of ENSO on low-frequency variability in the tropical Pacific, Int. J. Climatology, 33,1047-1052(corresponding author).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Y. Tang, S.-I. An, and W. Duan, 2013 : Climate Variability and Predictability at Various Time Scales, Advances in Meteorology, 2012, Article ID 857831, 1 page. doi:10.1155/2012/857831.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Im, S.-H., S.-I. An, M. Lengaigne, and Y, Noh, 2012: Seasonality of Tropical Instability Waves and Its Feedback to the Seasonal Cycle in the Tropical Eastern Pacific, The Scientific World Journal, 2012, Article ID 612048, 11 pages. doi:10.1100/2012/612048.(corresponding author)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ham, S., S.-Y. Jong, Y. Noh, S.-I. An, Y.-H. Byun, H.-S. Kang, J. Lee, and W.-T. Kwon, 2012 : Effects of fresh water run off on a trpical Pacific climate in the HAdGEM2. Asia-Pacific J. Atmos. Sci., 48, 457 -463.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An, S.-I., J.-W Kim, S.-H. Im, B.-M. Kim, and J.-H. Park, 2012 : Recent and Future Sea Surface Temperature Trends in Tropical Pacific Warm Pool and Cold Tongue Regions, Climate Dynamics, 39, 1373-1383.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dewitte B., J. Choi, S.-I. An, and S. Thual, 2012 : Vertical structure variability and equatorial waves during central Pacific and eastern Pacific El Ninos in a coupled general circulation model, Climate Dynamics, 38, 2275-2289.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Choi, J., S.-I. An, and S.-W. Yeh, 2012 : Decadal amplitude modulation of two types of ENSO and its relationship with the mean state, Climate Dynamics, 38, 2631-2644.(corresponding author)(June 1, 2012)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An, S.-I., J.-H. Park, B.-M. Kim, A. Timmermann, and F.-F. Jin, 2012 : Impacts of ocean gateway and basin width on Tertiary tropical climate variability in a prototype model, Theor, Appl. Climatol., 107, 155-164.(Jan. 9, 2012)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An, S.-I., 2011 : Atmospheric responses of Gill-type and Lindzen-Nigam models to global warming, J. Climate, 24, 6165-6173.(Dec 1, 2011)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Choi, J., S.-I. An, J.-S. Kug, and S.-W. Yeh, 2011 : The role of mean state on changes in El Nino’s flavor, Climate Dynamics, 37, 1205-1215.(corresponding author)(Sep. 1, 2011)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Thual, S., B. Dewitte, N. Ayoub, and S.-I. An, 2011 : Sensitivity of ENSO to stratification in a recharge-discharge conceptual model. J. Climate, 24, 4332-4349.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sung, M.-K., G.-H. Lim, J.-S. Kug, and S.-I. An, 2011 : A linkage between the NAO and its down stream development due to the existence of blocking ridge. J. Geophys. Res.- Atmosphere, 116, D11107.(corresponding author)(June. 4, 2011)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, B.-M., and S.-I. An, 2011: Understanding ENSO regime behavior upon an increase in the warm-pool temperature using a simple ENSO model. J. Climate, 24, 1438-1450.(corresponding author)(Mar. 1, 2011)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An, S.-I., and F.-F. Jin, 2011: Linear solutions for the frequency and amplitude modulation of ENSO by the annual cycle, Tellus, 63A, 238-243.(Mar. 1, 2011)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An, S.-I., and J. Choi, 2010 : Interaction between Equatorially Symmetric and Asymmetric Tropical Eastern Pacific SSTs, Theor. Appl. Climatol., 102, 151-158.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Belmadani, A., B. Dewitte and S.-I. An, 2010 : ENSO feedbacks and associated timescales of variabillity in a multi-model ensemble, J.Climate, 23, 3181-3204.(June 15, 2010)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Collins, M., S.-I. An, W. Cai, A. Ganachaud, E. Guilyardi, F.-F. Jin, M. Jochum, M. Lengaigne, S. Power, A. Timmermann, G. Vecchi, and A. Wittenberg, 2010: The impact of global warming on the tropical Pacific Ocean and El Nino, Nature Geoscience, 3, 391-397.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kug, J.-S., S.-I. An, Y.-G. Ham, and I.-S. Kang, 2010 : Changes in El Nino and La Nina teleconncetions over North Pacific-America in the global warming simulations, Theor. Appl. Climatol., 100, 275-282.(corresponding author)(May. 2010)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kug, J.-S., J. Choi, S.-I. An, F.-F. Jin and A.-T. Wittenberg, 2010 : Warm Pool and Cold Tongue El Nino events as simulated by the GFDL2.1 coupled GCM, J. Climate, 23, 1226-1239.(corresponding author)(Mar. 1, 2010)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An, S. -I., Y.-G. Ham, J.-S. Kug, A. Timmermann, J. Choi and I.-S. Kang, 2010 : The inverse effect of annual mean state and annual cycle changes on ENSO, J. Climate, 23, 1095-1110.(Mar. 1, 2010)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Choi, J., S.-I. An, B. Dewitte, and W.-W. Hsieh, 2009 : Interactive feedback between the tropical Pacific decadal oscillation and ENSO in a coupled general circulation model, J. Climate, 22, 6597-6611.(corresponding author)(Dec. 15. 2009)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dewitte, B., S. Thual, S.-W. Yeh, S.-I. An, B.-K. Moon, and Giese, 2009 : Low-frequency Variability of Temperature in the Vicinity of the Equatorial Pacific thermocline in SODA: Role of Equatorial Wave Dynamics and ENSO Asymmetry, J. Climate, 22, 5783-5795.(Nov. 15, 2009)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An, S. -I., and J. Choi, 2009 : Seasonal locking of the ENSO asymmetry and its influence on the seasonal cycle of the tropical eastern Pacific sea surface temperature. Atmospheric Research, 94, 3-9.(Sep. 2009).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An, S. -I., 2009 : A review of interdecadal changes in the nonlinearity of the El Nino-Southern Oscillation, Theor. Appl. Climatol., 97, 29-40.(June, 2009)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kug, J.-S., F.-F. Jin, and S.-I. An, 2009 : Two Types of El Nino Events: Cold Tongue El Nino and Warm Pool El Nino, J. Climate, 22, 1499-1515.(march 15, 2009).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An, S.-I., 2008 : Interannual Changes in the Variability of Tropical Pacific Instability Waves, Asia Pacific Journal of Atmospheric Sciences, 44, 249-258.(Aug, 2008)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An, S.-I., 2008 : Interannual Variations of the Tropical Ocean Instability Wave and ENSO, J. Climate. 21, 3680-3686.(Aug, 2008)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An, S.-I., 2008 : A mechanism for the multi-decadal climate oscillation in the North Pacific, Theor. Appl. Climatol., 91, 77-84.(Feb, 2008)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An, S.-I., J.-S. Kug, Y.-G. Ham, and I.-S. Kang, 2008 : Successive modulation of ENSO to the future greenhouse warming, J. Climate. 21, 3-21.(Jan. 15, 2008)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Timmermann, A., Y. Okumura, S.-I. An, A. Clement, B. Dong, E. Guilyardi, A. Hu, J. H. Jungclaus, M. Renold, T. F. Stocker, R. J. Stouffer, R. Sutton, S.-P. Xie, and J. Yin, 2007 : The influence of a weakening of the Atlantic meridional overturning circulation on ENSO, J. Climate. 20, 4899-4919.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Timmermann, A., S. J. Lorenz, S.-I. An, A. Clement, and S.-P. Xie, 2007 : The effect of orbital forcing on the mean climate and variability of the tropical Pacific, J. Climate. 20, 4147-4159.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yeh, S.-W., B. P. Kirtman, and S.-I. An, 2007 : Local versus non-local atmospheric weather noise and the North Pacific SST, Geophys. Res. Lett., 34, L14706.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dewitte, B., C. Cibot, C. Perigaud, S.-I. An, and L. Terray, 2007 : Interaction between near-annual and ENSO modes in a CGCM simulation : Role of the equatorial background mean state, J. Climate. 20, 1035-1052.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Holland, C. L., R. B. Scott, S.-I. An, and F. W. Taylor, 2007 : Propagating decadal sea surface temperature signal identified in modern proxy records of the tropical Pacific, Climate Dynamics, 28, 163-179.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An, S.-I., J.-S. Kug, A. Timmermann, I.-S. Kang, and O. Timm, 2007 : The influence of ENSO on the generation of decadal variability in the North Pacific, J. Climate. 20, 667-680.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An, S.-I., Z. Ye., and W. Hsieh, 2006 : Changes in the leading ENSO modes associated with the late 1970s climate shift : Role of surface zonal current, Geophys. Res. Lett., 33, L14609.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kug, J.-S., T. Li, S.-I. An, I.-S. Kang, J.-J. Luo, S. Masson, and T. Yamagata, 2006 : Role of the ENSO-Indian Ocean coupling on ENSO variability in a coupled GCM, Geophys. Res. Lett. 33, L09710.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kwon, M. H., J.-G, Jhun, B. Wang, S.-I. An, and J.-S. Kug, 2005 : Decadal change in relationship between east Asian summer monsson and western north Pacific summer monsoon, Geophys. Res. Lett., 32, L16709.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Wang, B., and S.-I. An, 2005 : A method for season-dependent modes of climate variability : S-EOF analysis, Geophys. Res. Lett., 32, L15710.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Timmermann, A., S.-I. An, U. Krebs, and H. Goosse, 2005 : ENSO suppression due to a weakening of the North Atlantic thermohaline circulation, J. Climate. 18, 3122-3139.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An, S.-I., and B. Wang, 2005 : The forced and intrinsic low-frequency models in the North Pacific, J. Climate. 18, 876-885.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kug, J.-S., S.-I. An, F.-F. Jin, and I.-S. Kang, 2005 : Preconditions for El Nino and La Nina onsets and their relation to Indian Ocean, Geophys. Res. Lett., 32, L05706.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An, S.-I., and W. W. Hsieh, and F.-F. Jin, 2005 : A nonlinear analysis of ENSO cycle and its interdecadal changes, J. Climate. 18, 3229-3239.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An, S.-I., 2005 : Relative roles of the equatorial upper ocean zonal current and thermocline in determining the timescale of the tropical climate system, Theor. Appl. Climatol., 81, 121-132.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An, S.-I., Y.-G. Ham, J.-S. Kug, F.-F. Jin, and I.-S. Kang, 2005 : El Nino-La Nina asymmetry in the coupled model Intercomparison project simulations, J. Climate. 18, 2617-2627.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An, S.-I., A. Timmermann, L. Bejarano, F.-F. Jin, F. Justino, Z. Liu, and A. W. Tudhope, 2004 : Modeling evidence for enhanced El Nino-Southern Oscillation amplitude during the Last Glacial Maximum, Paleoceanography. 19, PA4009.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An, S.-I., 2004 : Interdecadal changes in the El Nino-La Nina asymmetry, Geophy. Res. Lett., 31, L23210.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kang, I.-S., J.-S. Kug, S.-I. An and F.-F. Jin, 2004 : A Near-Annual Pacific Ocean Basin Mode, J. Climate. 17, 2478-2488.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An, S.-I., and F.-F. Jin, 2004 : Nonlinearity and asymmetry of ENSO, J. Climate. 17, 2399-2412.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An, S.-I., 2004 : A dynamic link between the basin-scale and zonal modes in the Tropical Indian Ocean, Theor. Appl. Climato., 78, 203-215.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kug, J.-S., I.-S. Kang and S.-I. An, 2003 : Symmetric and anti-symmetric mass exchanges between the equatorial and off-equatorial Pacific associated with ENSO, J. Geophy. Res. -Oceans. 108, C8, 3284.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An, S.-I., 2003 : Conditional Maximum Covariance Analysis and its Application to the Tropical Indian Ocean SST and Surface wind Stress Anomalies, J. Climate. 16, 2932-2938.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jin, F.-F., S.-I. An, A. Timmermann, and J. Zhao, 2003 : Strong El Nino events and nonlinear dynamical heating, Geophys. Res. Letts. 30, 1120.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jin, F.-F., J.-S. Kug, S.-I. An and I.-S. Kang, 2003 : A near-annual coupled ocean-atmosphere mode in the equatorial Pacific ocean, Geophys. Res. Letts. 30, 1080.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Wang, B., and S.-I. An, 2002 : A mechanism for decadal changes of ENSO behavior : Roles of background wind changes, Climate Dyn. 18, 475-486.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An, S.-I., and I.-S. Kang, 2001 : Tropical Pacific Basin-Wide Adjustment and Oceanic Waves, Geophy. Res. Lett., 28, 3975-3978.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Wang, B., and S.-I. An, 2001 : Why the Properties of El Nino changed During the Late 1970s, Geophy. Res. Lett., 28, 3421-3432.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An, S.-I., and F.-F. Jin, 2001 : Collective Role of Thermocline and Zonal Advective Feedbacks in the ENSO Mode, J. Climate, 14, 3421-3432.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An, S.-I., and I.-S. Kang, 2001 : Sensitivity of the Equatorial Air-Sea Coupled System to the Zonal Phase Difference between SST and Wind Stress, Adv. Atmos. Sci., 18, 155-165.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kang, I.-S., S.-I. An and F.-F. Jin, 2001 : A Systematic Approximation of the SST Anomaly Equation for ENSO, J. Meteor. Soc. Japan. 79, 1-10.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An, S.-I., and B. Wang, 2001 : Mechanisms of locking the El Nino and La Nina mature phases to boreal winter, J. Climate. 27, 2164-2176.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An, S.-I., and F.-F. Jin, 2000 : An eigen analysis of the interdecadal changes in the structure and frequency of ENSO mode, Geophys. Res. Lett., 27, 1573-1576.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An, S.-I., and B. Wang, 2000 : Interdecadal change of the structure of the ENSO mode and it impact on the ENSO frequency, J. Climate. 13, 2044-2055.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An, S.-I., and I.-S. Kang, 2000 : A further investigation of the recharge oscillator paradigm for ENSO using a simple coupled model with the zonal mean and eddy separated, J. Climate. 13, 1987-1993.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An, S.-I, 2000 : On the slow mode in a simple air-sea coupled model : The Sensitivity to the zonal pahse difference between the SST and the atmospheric heating, J. Meteor. Soc. Japan. 78, 159-165.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An, S.-I., F.-F. Jin, and I.-S. Kang, 1999 : The role of zonal advection feedback in phase transition and growth of ENSO in the Cane-Zebiak model, J. Meteor. Soc. Japan. 77, 1151-1160.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jin, F.-F. and S.-I. An, 1999 : Thermocline and zonal advection feedbacks within the equatorial ocean recharge oscillator model for ENSO, Geophys. Res. Lett., 26, 2989-2992.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kang, I.-S., and S.-I. An, 1998 : Kelvin and Rossby wave contributions to the SST oscillation of ENSO, J. Climate. 11, 2461-2469.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An, S.-I. and J. Choi, 2012 : On the Development of 2012 EI Nino, Atmosphere. 22, 465-472( Korean).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An, S.-I., K.-J. Ha, K.-H. Seo, S.-W. Yeh, S.-K. Min, and C.-H. Ho, 2011 : A review of recent climate trends and causes over the Korean Peninsula, Climate Change Research, 2(4), 237-251(Korean).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kug, J.-S., S.-I. An, 2010 : Ocean dynamic processes responsible for the interannual variability of the tropical Indian Ocean SST associated with ENSO, Atmosphere, 20, 211-219.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kang, I.-S., Yang-Mi Lee, and S.-I. An, 1995 : Interannual variability of Typhoon activity over the western Pacific and El Nino, J. Korean Meteor. Soc. 31, 15-26.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kang, I.-S., S.-I. An, C.-H. Joung, S.-C. Yoon, and S.-M. Lee, 1989 : 30-60 day oscillation signal appearing in climatological variation of outgoing longwave radiation around East Asian region during Northern Summer, J. Korean Meteor. Soc., 25, 221-232.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>신동빈</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/people/dongbinshin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/people/dongbinshin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;연구분야&#34;&gt;연구분야&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;위성기상&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;원격탐사&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;대기복사&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;학력&#34;&gt;학력&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ph.D.&lt;/strong&gt; (1999) Atmospheric Sciences, Texas A&amp;amp;M University, College Station, TX, USA&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;M.S.&lt;/strong&gt; (1989) Meteorology, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B.S.&lt;/strong&gt; (1987) Astronomy and Meteorology, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;연구경력&#34;&gt;연구경력&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2014-present : Professor, Department of Atmospheric Sciences, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2007-2013  : Associate Professor, Department of Atmospheric Sciences, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2002-2007 : Research Professor, Center for Earth Observing and Space Research, School of Computational Sciences, George Mason University, Fairfax, VA, USA.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2001-2002  : Research Scientist, Dept. of Atmospheric Science, Colorado State University, Fort Collins, CO, USA.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2000 : Assistant Research Scientist, Center for Earth Observing and Space Research, School of Computational Sciences, George Mason University, Fairfax, VA, USA.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;담당과목&#34;&gt;담당과목&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;위성기상학&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;마이크로파복사 및 원격탐사이론&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;논문&#34;&gt;논문&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hong, S.-B., D.-B. Shin, B.-H. Park, and D.-W. So, 2016: Development of prototype algorithms for quantitative precipitation nowcasts from AMI onboard the GEO-KOMPSAT-2A satellite, IEEE Transactions on Geoscience and Remote Sensing, 54(12),7149-7156&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, S.-W., D.-B. Shin, and Y.-J. Choi, 2016: Effects of the three-dimensional hydrometeor distributions of precipitating clouds on passive microwave rainfall estimations, IEEE Transactions on Geoscience and Remote Sensing, 54(4), 1957-1966.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lee, Y.-R., D.-B. Shin, J.-H. Kim, and H.-S. Park, 2015: Precipitation estimation over radar gap areas based on satellite and adjacent radar observations, Atmospheric Measurement Techniques, 8, 719-728.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yoo, J.-M., Y.-R. Lee, D. Kim, S.-M. Oh, M.-J. Jeong, W.R. Stockwell, P. K. Kundu, D.-B. Shin, and S.-J. Lee, 2014: New indices for wet scavenging of air pollutants (O3, CO, NO2, SO2, and PM10) by summertime rain, Atmospheric Environment, 82, 226-237.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, J.-H., D.-B. Shin, and C. Kummerow, 2013: Impacts of a-priori databases using six WRF microphysics schemes on passive microwave rainfall retrievals. Journal of Atmospheric and Oceanic Technology, 30, 2367-2381.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Park, H.-J., D.-B. Shin, and J.-M. Yoo, 2013: Atmospheric water balance over oceanic regions as estimated from satellite, merged, and reanalysis data. J. Geophys. Res., 118, 3495-3505, doi:10.1002/jgrd.50414.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lee, Y.-R., J.-M. Yoo, M.-J. Jeong, Y.-I. Won, T. Hearty, and D.-B. Shin, 2013: Comparison between MODIS and AIRS/AMSU satellite-derived surface skin temperatures. Atmospheric Measurement Techniques, 6, 445-455.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yoo, J.-M., Y.-I. Won, M.-J. Jeong, K.-M. Kim, D.-B. Shin, Y.-R. Lee, and Y.-J. Cho, 2013: Intensity of climate variability derived from the satellite and MERRA reanalysis temperatures: AO, ENSO, and QBO. Journal of Atmospheric and Solar-Terrestrial Physics, 95-96, 15-27, doi:10.1016/j.jastp.2013.01.002.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chiu, L. S., S. Gao and D.-B. Shin, 2013: Climate-Scale Oceanic Rainfall Based on Passive Microwave Radiometry, Satellite-based Applications on Climate Change, J. Qu, A. Powell, M.V.K. Sivakumar (Eds), Springer, 225-245, ISBN: 978-94-007-5871-1&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, J.-H, D.-B. Shin and K.-W. Jin, 2012: Impact of proxy variables of the rain column height on monthly oceanic rainfall estimations from passive microwave sensors. International Journal of Remote Sensing, 33(12), 3693 - 3712, doi:10.1080/01431161.2011.631952&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yoo. J.-M., Y.-I. Won, Y.-J. Cho, M.-J. Jeong, D.-B. Shin, S.-J. Lee, Y.-R. Lee, S.-M. Oh, and S.J. Ban, 2011: Temperature trends in the skin/surface, mid-troposphere and low stratosphere near Korea from satellite and ground measurements. Asia Pacific Journal of Atmospheric Sciences, 47(5), 439-455, doi:10.1007/s13143-011-0029-4.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Shin, D.-B., J.-H. Kim, and H.-J. Park, 2011: Agreement between monthly precipitation estimates from TRMM satellite, NCEP reanalysis, and merged gauge?satellite analysis, J. Geophys. Res., 116, D16105, doi:10.1029/2010JD015483.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Shin, D.-B., 2011: Spatial information of high frequency brightness temperatures for passive microwave rainfall retrievals. International Journal of Remote Sensing, 32(19), 5347-5363, doi:10.1080/01431161.2010.498451.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yoo, J.-M., M.-J. Jeong,, Y.-M. Hur, and D.-B. Shin, 2010: Improved fog detection from satellite in the presence of clouds. Asia Pacific Journal of Atmospheric Sciences, 46(1), 29-40.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Shin, D.-B., K. P. Bowman, J.-M. Yoo and L. S. Chiu, 2009: Variability of passive microwave radiometric signatures at different spatial resolutions and its implication for rainfall estimation. IEEE Transactions on Geoscience and Remote Sensing, 47(6), 1575-1584.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Shin, D.-B., L. S. Chiu and P. Clemente-Colon, 2008: Effects of atmospheric water and surface wind on passive microwave retrievals of sea ice concentration: a simulation study. International Journal of Remote Sensing, 29(19), 5717-5731.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Shin, D.-B. and L. S. Chiu, 2008: Effects of TRMM boost on oceanic rainfall estimates based on microwave emission brightness temperature histograms (METH). Journal of Atmospheric and Oceanic Technology, 25(10), 1888-1893.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Battaglia, A., F. Prodi, F. Porcu and D.-B. Shin, April 2007: 3D effects in microwave radiative transport inside precipitating clouds: modeling and applications, Measuring Precipitation from Space: EURAINSAT and the future, V. Levizzani, P.Bauer and J. Turk (Eds), Advances in Global Change Research, 28, Springer, 113-126.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chiu, L. and D.-B. Shin, 2006: Surface Rain Rates from TRMM Satellite Algorithms, Earth Science Satellite Remote Sensing, Vol. 1: Science and instruments, J. Qu, W. Gao, M. Kafatos, R. Murphy, and V. Salomonson (Eds), London, Springer.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Shin, D.-B. and C. Kummerow, 2003: Parametric rainfall retrieval algorithms for passive microwave radiometers. Journal of Applied Meteorology, 42, 1480-1496.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Battaglia, A., C. Kummerow, D.-B. Shin and C. Williams, 2003: Constraining microwave brightness temperatures by radar bright band observations. Journal of Atmospheric and Oceanic Technology, 20, 856-871.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Shin, D.-B., L. S. Chiu and M. Kafatos, 2001: Comparison of the monthly precipitation derived from the TRMM satellite. Geophysical Research Letter, 28(5), 795-798.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kummerow, C., Y. Hong, W. S. Olson, S. Yang, R. F. Adler, J. McCollum, R. Ferraro, G. Petty, D.-B. Shin and T. T. Wilheit, 2001: The evolution of the Goddard profiling algorithm (GPROF) for rain estimation from passive microwave sensors. Journal of Applied Meteorology, 40, 1801-1820.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Shin, D.-B., K. P. Bowman and G. R. North, 2000: A summary of reflectivity profiles from the first year of TRMM radar data. Journal of Climate, 13, 4072-4086.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Harris, G., K. P. Bowman and D.-B. Shin, 2000: Comparison of freezing-level altitudes from the NCEP Reanalysis with TRMM precipitation radar brightband data, Journal of Climate, 13, 4137-4148.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Shin, D.-B., and G. R. North, 2000: Errors incurred in sampling a cyclostationary Field. Journal of Atmospheric and Oceanic Technology, 17, 656-664.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>홍진규</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/people/jinkyuhong/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 11:39:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/people/jinkyuhong/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;연구분야&#34;&gt;연구분야&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;탄소 및 물 순환&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;도시 기후 및 도시 환경&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;생태계-대기 상호 작용&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;에너지-기후 상호 작용&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;교육&#34;&gt;교육&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;도시기후학&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;미기상학/경계층기상학&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;대기관측&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;생물-대기 상호작용&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;학력&#34;&gt;학력&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ph.D.&lt;/strong&gt; (2005) Department of Atmospheric Sciences, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;M.S.&lt;/strong&gt; (1999) Department of Atmospheric Sciences, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B.S.&lt;/strong&gt; (1997) Department of Astronomy and Atmospheric Sciences, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Science Genealogy: &lt;a href=&#34;https://academictree.org/chemistry/tree.php?pid=826516&amp;amp;pnodecount=7&amp;amp;cnodecount=2&amp;amp;fontsize=1&#34;&gt;https://academictree.org/chemistry/tree.php?pid=826516&amp;amp;pnodecount=7&amp;amp;cnodecount=2&amp;amp;fontsize=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;경력&#34;&gt;경력&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(현) 국가물관리위원회 자문위원&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(현) 서울시 환경영향평가위원&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(현) 과학기술정보통신부 에너지환경 R&amp;amp;D추진위원회 위원&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(현) 한국연구재단 기후적응 전문위원&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(현) Member of the study group on Integrated Energy Serices (SG-ENE), WMO Services Commission (SERCOM), World Meteorological Organization&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(현) Expert Member of WMO flux measurements for agriculture with a focus on GHG emissions (ET2.2, CAgM)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(현) 교수, 연세대학교 대기과학과&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2010 - 2012 : 선임연구원, 국가수리과학연구소&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2006 - 2008 : Postdoctoral Researcher, Univ. of Georgia, USA&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;selected-publications&#34;&gt;Selected Publications&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, J., J. Lee, J.-W. Hong, J. Hong, J. Koo, J. Kim, J. Yun, S. Nam, J. Jung, T. Choi, and B. Lee (2020) Evaluation of land-atmosphere processes of the Polar WRF in the summertime Arctic tundra, Atmospheric Research, 240, 104946, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.atmosres.2020.104946&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.atmosres.2020.104946&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lee, J., J. Hong, Y. Noh, and P. Jiménez (2020) Implementation of a roughness sublayer parameterization in the Weather Research and Forecasting model (WRF version 3.7.1) and its validation for regional climate simulations, Geoscientific Model Development, 13, 521-536.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hong, J.-W., S. D. Lee, K. M. Lee, and J. Hong (2020) Seasonal variation of surface energy and CO2 flux over a high-rise high-population residential urban area in East Asian monsoon region, International Journal of Climatology, 40, 4384-4407, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/joc.6463&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/joc.6463&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hong, J.-W., J. Hong, J. Chun, Y. Lee, L. Chang, J. Lee, K. Yi, Y. Park, Y. Byun, and S. Joo (2019) Comparative assessment of net CO2 exchange across an urbanization gradient in Korea based on in situ observation, Carbon Balance and Management, https//doi.org/10.1186/s13021-019-0128-6.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hong, J.-W., J. Hong, E. Kwon, and D. Yoon (2019) Temporal dynamics of urban heat island correlated with the socio-economic development over the past half-century in Seoul, Korea, Environmental Pollution, 254, 112934, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10546-019-00452-5&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10546-019-00452-5&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lee, J. H., J.-W. Hong, K. M. Lee, J. Hong, E. Velasco, Y. Lim, J. Lee. K. Nam, and J. Park (2019) Ceilometer monitoring of boundary layer height in Seoul and its application to evaluate the dilution effect on air pollution, Boundary-Layer Meteorology, 171, 435-455.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kent, C., K. Lee, H. C. Ward, J.-W. Hong, J. Hong, D. Gatey, and S. Grimmond (2018) Aerodynamic roughness variation with vegetation: Analysis in a suburban neighbourhood and a city park, &lt;em&gt;Urban Ecosystems&lt;/em&gt;, 21, 227-243.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Song, I., U. Byun, J. Hong and S. Park (2018) Domain-size and top-height dependence in regional predictions for East Asia in spring, &lt;em&gt;Atmospheric Science Letters&lt;/em&gt;, 19, e799.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lee, C., K. Han, J. Yeom, K. Lee, M. Seo, J. Hong, J.-W. Hong, K. Lee, J. Shin, I. Shim, J. Chun, and J.-L. Roujean (2018) Surface albedo from the geostationary Communication, Ocean and Meteorological Satellite (COMS)/Meteorological Imager (MI) observation system, &lt;em&gt;GIScience &amp;amp; Remote Sensing&lt;/em&gt;, 28, 38-62.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lee, J. and J. Hong (2016) Implementation of spaceborne LiDAR-retrieved canopy height in the WRF model, &lt;em&gt;Journal of Geophysical Research&lt;/em&gt;, 121, 6863–6876, doi: 10.1002/2015JD024299.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hong, J.-W. and J. Hong (2016) Changes in the Seoul metropolitan area urban heat environment with residential redevelopment, &lt;em&gt;Journal of Applied Meteorology and Climatology&lt;/em&gt;, 55, 1091-1106&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hong, J. and W. S. Kim (2015) Weather impacts on electric power load: Partial phase synchronisation analysis, &lt;em&gt;Meteorological Applications&lt;/em&gt;, 22, 811-816.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lee, J., H. Shin, S. Hong, P. Jimenez, J. Dudhia, and J. Hong (2015) Impacts of sub-grid-scale orography parameterization on simulated surface-layer wind and monsoonal precipitation in the high-resolution WRF model. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Geophysical Research&lt;/em&gt;, 120, 644–653.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lee, W. and J. Hong (2015) A hybrid dynamic and fuzzy time series model for mid-term power load forecasting, &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Electrical Power &amp;amp; Energy Systems&lt;/em&gt;, 64, 1057-1062.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Shim, C., J. Hong, J. Hong, Y. Kim, M. Kang, B. Thakuri, Y. Kim, J. Chun (2014) Evaluation of MODIS GPP over a complex ecosystem in East Asia: a case of Gwangneung flux tower in Korea, &lt;em&gt;Advances in Space Research&lt;/em&gt;, 54, 2296-2308.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hong, J., K. Takagi, T. Ohta, and Y. Kodama (2014) Wet surface resistance of forest canopy in monsoon Asia: Implications for eddy covariance measurement of evapotranspiration, &lt;em&gt;Hydrological Processes&lt;/em&gt;, 28, 37-42.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lim, Y., J. Hong, and T. Lee (2012) Spin-up behavior of soil moisture content over East Asia in a land surface model, &lt;em&gt;Meteorology and Atmospheric Physics&lt;/em&gt;, 118, 151-161.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hong, J., J. Kim and Y.-H. Byun (2012) Uncertainty in carbon exchange modeling in a forest canopy due to kB-1 parameterizations, &lt;em&gt;Quarterly Journal of the Royal Meteorological Society&lt;/em&gt;, 138, 699-706.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lim, Y., K. Byun, T. Lee, H. Kwon, J. Hong, and J. Kim (2012) A land data assimilation system using MODIS-derived land data and its application to numerical weather prediction, &lt;em&gt;Asia-Pacific Journal of Atmospheric Sciences&lt;/em&gt;, 48, 83-95.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hong, J. and J. Kim (2011) Impact of the Asian monsoon climate on ecosystem carbon and water exchanges: A wavelet analysis and its ecosystem modeling implication, &lt;em&gt;Global Change Biology&lt;/em&gt;, 17, 1900-1916.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kwon, H., J. Kim, J. Hong, and J. Lim (2010) Influence of the Asian monsoon on interannual variability of net ecosystem carbon exchange in two major plant functional types in Korea, &lt;em&gt;Biogeosciences&lt;/em&gt;, 7, 1493-1504.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hong, J., J. Kim, H. Ishikawa, and Y. Ma (2010) Surface layer similarity in the nocturnal boundary layer: The application of Hilbert-Huang transform, &lt;em&gt;Biogeosciences&lt;/em&gt;, 7, 1271-1278.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hong, J. and J. Kim (2010) Numerical study of surface energy partitioning on the Tibet plateau: Comparative analysis of two biosphere models, &lt;em&gt;Biogeosciences&lt;/em&gt;, 7, 557-568.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dias, N., J. Hong, M. Leclerc, T. A. Black, Z. Nesic, and P. Krishnan (2009) A simple method for scalar flux estimates over forests, &lt;em&gt;Boundary-Layer Meteorology&lt;/em&gt;, 132, 401-414.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hong, J. and J. Kim (2008) Scale-dependency of surface fluxes in an atmospheric mesoscale model: Effect of spatial heterogeneity in atmospheric conditions, &lt;em&gt;Nonlinear Processes in Geophysics&lt;/em&gt;, 15, 965-975.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hong, J. and J. Kim (2008) Simulation of surface radiation balance on the Tibetan Plateau, &lt;em&gt;Geophysical Research Letters&lt;/em&gt;, 35, L08814, doi:10.1029/2008GL033613.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hong, J., J. Kim, D. H. Lee, and J. H. Lim (2008) Estimation of the storage and advection effects on H2O and CO2 exchanges in a hilly KoFlux forest catchment, &lt;em&gt;Water Resources Research&lt;/em&gt;, 44, W01426, doi:10.1029/2007WR006408.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hong, J., T. J. Choi, H. Ishikawa, and J. Kim (2004) Turbulence Structures in the Near-Neutral Surface Layer on the Tibetan Plateau. &lt;em&gt;Geophysical Research Letters&lt;/em&gt;, 31, L15016, doi:10.1029/2004GL019935.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Choi, T. J., J. Hong, J. Kim, H. C. Lee, J. Asanuma, H. Ishikawa, G. Zhiqiu, Y. Ma, J. Wang, T. Koike, T. Yasunari, K. Ueno, and O. Tsukamoto (2004) Turbulent Exchange of Heat, Water Vapor and Momentum Over a Tibetan Prairie by Eddy Covariance and Flux-Variance Measurements. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Geophysical Research&lt;/em&gt;, 109, D211106, doi:10.1029/2004JD004767.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hong, J., J. Kim, A. Miyata, and Y. Harazono (2002) Basic Characteristics of Canopy Turbulence in a Homogeneous Rice Paddy, &lt;em&gt;Journal of Geophysical Research&lt;/em&gt;, 107(D22), 4623, doi:10.1029/2002JD002223.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>박상훈</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/people/sanghunpark/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/people/sanghunpark/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;연구분야&#34;&gt;연구분야&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;수치모형&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;중규모 기상학&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;학력&#34;&gt;학력&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ph.D.&lt;/strong&gt; (2009) Department of Atmospheric Sciences, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;M.S.&lt;/strong&gt; (2001) Department of Atmospheric Sciences, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B.S.&lt;/strong&gt; (1999)  Department of Astro and Atmospheric Sciences, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;연구경력&#34;&gt;연구경력&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2014-2017: Project Scientist, National Center for Atmospheric Research, Boulder, USA&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2013-2013: Postdoctoral Fellow, Earth System Laboratory, National Center for Atmospheric Research, Boulder, USA&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2011-2012: Advanced Study Program (ASP), National Center for Atmospheric Research, Boulder, USA&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;담당과목&#34;&gt;담당과목&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;대기역학&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;전산유체역학&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;논문&#34;&gt;논문&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Park, S.-H., J.-H. Kim, R. D. Sharman and J. B. Klemp, 2016 : Update of upper-level turbulence forecast by reducing unphysical components of topography in the numerical weather prediction model, Geophys. Res. Lett., 43, 7718-7724, DOI: 10.1002/2016GL069446&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Klemp, J. B., Skamarock, W. C. and S.-H. Park, 2015: Idealized Global Nonhydrostatic Test Case on a Reduced Radius Sphere. J. Adv. Model. Earth Sys., 7, 1155-1177&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Skamarock, W. C., S.-H. Park, J. B. Klemp and C. Snyder, 2014: Atmospheric Kinetic Energy Spectra from Global High-Resolution Nonhydrostatic Simulations. J. Atmos. Sci., 71, 4369-4381&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Park, S.-H., J. B. Klemp and W. C. Skamarock, 2014 : Normal mode baroclinc wave simulation on nested-grids and variable-resolution Voronoi meshes. Mon Wea. Rev. 142, 3614-3634.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Park, S.-H., Skamarock, W. C., J. B. Klemp, L. D. Fowler and M. G. Duda, 2013 : Evaluation of global atmospheric solvers using extensions of the Jablonowski and Williamson baroclinic wave test case. Mon Wea. Rev., 141, 3116-3129&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>송하준</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/people/hajoonsong/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 11:39:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/people/hajoonsong/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;연구분야&#34;&gt;연구분야&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;대기-해양 상호관계&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;탄소순환&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;대기-해양 모델링&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;자료동화&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;해양순환&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;학력&#34;&gt;학력&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ph.D.&lt;/strong&gt; (2011) Scripps Institution of Oceanography, University of California, San Diego, USA&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B.S.&lt;/strong&gt; (2005) Department of Atmospheric Sciences, Yonsei University, Seoul, South Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;연구경력&#34;&gt;연구경력&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2018.3 - : Assistant/Associate Professor, Department of Atmospheric Sciences, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2019.2 : Visiting Professor, MIT, Cambridge, USA&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2018.7 - 2018.8 : Visiting Professor, MIT, Cambridge, USA&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2013-2018: Research Scientist / Postdoctoral Associate, MIT, Cambridge, USA&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2011-2013: Postdoctoral Associate, University of California, Santa Cruz, USA&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2005-2011: Assistant Researcher, Scripps Institution of Oceanography, La Jolla, USA&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2005 : Research assistant, Korea Institute of Ocean Science &amp;amp; Technology, Ansan, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;담당과목&#34;&gt;담당과목&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hajsong.github.io/ATM2106/&#34;&gt;대기 해양 순환&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hajsong.github.io/ATM9107/&#34;&gt;해양 모델링&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;대기 해양 상호작용&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;해양 물리&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hajsong.github.io/ATM4110/&#34;&gt;기상 프로그래밍&lt;/a&gt;, 2018&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;논문&#34;&gt;논문&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kwak, K., &lt;strong&gt;Song, H.&lt;/strong&gt;, Marshall, J., Seo, H. and McGillicuddy, D. J. Jr. (2021)}: Suppressed pCO2 in the Southern Ocean due to the interaction between current and wind. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Geophysical Research: Oceans&lt;/em&gt;, 126, e2021JC017884&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Al-Shehhi, M.R., &lt;strong&gt;H. Song&lt;/strong&gt;, J.R. Scott and J. Marshall (2021). Water mass transformation and overturning circulation in the Arabian Gulf. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Physical Oceanography&lt;/em&gt;, 51(11), 3513-3527&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Seo, H., &lt;strong&gt;H. Song&lt;/strong&gt;, L.W. O&amp;rsquo;Neill, M.R. Mazloff and B.D. Cornuelle (2021). Impacts of ocean currents on the South Indian Ocean extratropical storm track through the relative wind effect. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Climate&lt;/em&gt;, 34(22), 9093-9113&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hur, I., M. KIM, &lt;strong&gt;K. Kwak&lt;/strong&gt;, H.M. Sung, Y-H Byun, &lt;strong&gt;H. Song&lt;/strong&gt; and C. Yoo (2021). Hadley circulation in the present and future climate simulations of the K-ACE model. &lt;em&gt;Asia-Pacific Journal of Atmospheric Sciences&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s13143-021-00256-z&#34; title=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s13143-021-00256-z&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s13143-021-00256-z&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tak, Y. J.&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;H. Song&lt;/strong&gt;, Y. K. Cho (2021). Impact of the reemergence of North Pacific subtropical mode water on the multi-year modulation of marine heatwaves in the North Pacific Ocean during winter and early spring. &lt;em&gt;Environmental Research Letters&lt;/em&gt;, 16(7), 074036&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Doddridge, E. W. , J. Marshall, &lt;strong&gt;H. Song&lt;/strong&gt;, J-M Campin and M. Kelley (2021). Southern Ocean heat storage, reemergence, and winter sea ice decline induced by summertime winds. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Climate&lt;/em&gt; 34 (4), 1403-1415&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Gupta, M., J. Marshall, &lt;strong&gt;H. Song&lt;/strong&gt;, J-M Campin and G. Meneghello (2020). Sea‐Ice Melt Driven by Ice‐Ocean Stresses on the Mesoscale, &lt;em&gt;Journal of Geophysical Research: Oceans&lt;/em&gt; 125 (11), e2020JC016404&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Wang, S., Kranz, S. A., Kelly, T. B., &lt;strong&gt;Song, H.&lt;/strong&gt;, Stukel, M. R., &amp;amp; Cassar, N. (2020). Lagrangian studies of net community production: The effect of diel and multiday nonsteady state factors and vertical fluxes on O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/Ar in a dynamic upwelling region. Journal of Geophysical Research: Biogeosciences, 125, e2019JG005569. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2019JG005569&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2019JG005569&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Song, H.&lt;/strong&gt;, Marshall, J., McGillicuddy, D. J., &amp;amp; Seo, H. (2020). Impact of Current-Wind Interaction on Vertical Processes in the Southern Ocean. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Geophysical Research: Oceans&lt;/em&gt;, 125(4), [e2020JC016046].&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Seo, H., A. C. Subramanian, &lt;strong&gt;Song, H.&lt;/strong&gt;, Chowdary, J. S. (2019), Coupled effects of ocean current on wind stress in the Bay of Bengal: Eddy energetics and upper ocean stratification, &lt;em&gt;Deep-Sea Res. Pt II&lt;/em&gt;, 168, 104617&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Song, H.&lt;/strong&gt;, J. Marshall, J-M Campin and D. J. McGillicuddy (2019), Impact of near-inertial waves on vertical mixing and air-sea CO2 fluxes in the Southern Ocean. &lt;em&gt;J. Geophys. Res. Oceans.&lt;/em&gt;, 124, 4605–4617&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Doddridge, E. W., J. Marshall, &lt;strong&gt;H. Song&lt;/strong&gt;, M. Kelley and L. Nazarenko (2019), Eddy compensation dampens Southern Ocean SST response to westerly wind trends. &lt;em&gt;Geophys. Res. Lett.&lt;/em&gt;, 46, 4365-4377&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kelly, T, R. Goericke, M. Kahru, &lt;strong&gt;H. Song&lt;/strong&gt; and M. R. Stukel: CCE II (2018), Spatial and interannual variability in export efficiency and the biological pump in an eastern boundary current upwelling system with substantial lateral advection. &lt;em&gt;Deep-Sea Res. Pt I&lt;/em&gt;, 140, 14-25&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Song, H.&lt;/strong&gt;, M. C. Long, P. Gaube, I. Frenger, J. Marshall and D. J. McGillicuddy Jr. (2018), Seasonal variation in the correlation between anomalies of sea level and chlorophyll in the Antarctic Circumpolar Current region. &lt;em&gt;Geophys. Res. Lett.&lt;/em&gt;, 45, 5011-5019&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Stukel, M. R., &lt;strong&gt;H. Song&lt;/strong&gt;, R. Goericke, A. J. Miller (2018), The role of subduction and gravitational sinking in particle export, carbon sequestration, and the remineralization length scale in the California Current Ecosystem. &lt;em&gt;Limnol. Oceanogr.&lt;/em&gt;, 63, 363-383, doi:10.1002/lno.10636&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Stukel, M. R., L. I. Aluwihare, K. A. Barbeau, A. M. Chekalyuk, R. Goericke, A. J. Miller, M. D. Ohman, A. Ruacho, &lt;strong&gt;H. Song&lt;/strong&gt;, B. Stephens and M. R. Landry (2017), Deepwater mesoscale fronts enhance export in the California Current Ecosystem. &lt;em&gt;PNAS&lt;/em&gt;, 114, 1252-1257&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mattern, J. P., &lt;strong&gt;H. Song&lt;/strong&gt;, C. A. Edward, A. M. Moore and J. Fiechter (2017), Data assimilation of physical and chlorophyll observations in the California Current System using two biogeochemical models. &lt;em&gt;Ocean Model.&lt;/em&gt;, 109, 55-71&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Song, H.&lt;/strong&gt;, J. Marshall, D. R. Munro, S. Dutkiewicz, C. Sweeney, D. J. McGillicuddy Jr. and U. Hausmann (2016): Mesoscale modulation of air-sea CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; flux in Drake Passage. &lt;em&gt;J. Geophys. Res. Oceans.&lt;/em&gt;, 121, 6635-6649&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Song, H.&lt;/strong&gt;, C. A. Edwards, A. M. Moore and J. Fietcher (2016), Data assimilation in a coupled physicalbiogeochemical model of the California Current System using an incremental lognormal 4-dimensional variational approach: Part 1, Model formulation and biological data assimilation twin experiments. &lt;em&gt;Ocean Model.&lt;/em&gt;, 106, 131-145&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Song, H.&lt;/strong&gt;, C. A. Edwards, A. M. Moore and J. Fietcher (2016), Data assimilation in a coupled physicalbiogeochemical model of the California Current System using an incremental lognormal 4-dimensional variational approach: Part 2, Joint physical and biological data assimilation twin experiments. &lt;em&gt;Ocean Model.&lt;/em&gt;, 106, 146-158&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Song, H.&lt;/strong&gt;, C. A. Edwards, A. M. Moore and J. Fietcher (2016), Data assimilation in a coupled physicalbiogeochemical model of the California Current System using an incremental lognormal 4-dimensional variational approach: Part 3, Assimilation in a realistic context using satellite and in situ observations. &lt;em&gt;Ocean Model.&lt;/em&gt;, 106, 159-172&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Song, H.&lt;/strong&gt;, J. Marshall, M. J. Follows, S. Dutkiewicz and G. Forget (2016), Source waters for the highly productive Patagonian shelf in the southwestern Atlantic. &lt;em&gt;J. Mar. Syst.&lt;/em&gt;, 158, 120-128&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Song, H.&lt;/strong&gt;, J. Marshall, P. Gaube and D. J. McGillicuddy (2015), Anomalous chlorofluorocarbon uptake by mesoscale eddies in the Drake Passage region. &lt;em&gt;J. Geophys. Res&lt;/em&gt;. Oceans, 120, 1065-1078&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Edwards, C. A., A. M. Moore, J. P. Mattern, J. Fiechter, &lt;strong&gt;H. Song&lt;/strong&gt;, and M. G. Jacox (2015), Hindcasting and nowcasting the physical and biological state of the California Current System. &lt;em&gt;CalCOFI Rep.&lt;/em&gt;, 56, 11-12&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Miller, A. J., &lt;strong&gt;H. Song&lt;/strong&gt; and A. C. Subramanian (2015), The physical oceanographic environment during the CCELTER Years: Changes in climate and concepts. &lt;em&gt;Deep-Sea Res. Pt II&lt;/em&gt;, 112, 6-17&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Song, H.&lt;/strong&gt;, I. Hoteit, B. D. Cornuelle X. Luo and A. C. Subramanian (2013), An Adjoint-Based Adaptive Ensemble Kalman Filter. &lt;em&gt;Mon. Wea. Rev.&lt;/em&gt;, 141, 3343-3359&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Song, H.&lt;/strong&gt;, C. A. Edwards, A. M. Moore and J. Fietcher (2012), Four-dimensional variational data assimilation of positive-definite oceanic variables using a logarithm transformation. &lt;em&gt;Ocean Model.&lt;/em&gt;, 54-55, 1-17&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Song, H.&lt;/strong&gt;, A. J. Miller, S. McClatchie, E. D. Weber, K. M. Nieto and D. M. Checkley Jr. (2012), Application of a data-assimilation model to variability of Pacific sardine spawning and survivor habitats with ENSO in the California Current System. &lt;em&gt;J. Geophys. Res.&lt;/em&gt;, 117, C03009&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Subramanian, A. C., I. Hoteit, B. D. Cornuelle and &lt;strong&gt;H. Song&lt;/strong&gt; (2012), Linear vs Nonlinear Filtering with scale selective corrections for balanced dynamics in a simple atmospheric model. &lt;em&gt;J. Atmos. Sci.&lt;/em&gt;, 69, 3405-3419&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Song, H.&lt;/strong&gt;, A. J. Miller, B. D. Cornuelle and E. Di Lorenzo (2011), Changes in upwelling and its water sources in the California Current System driven by different wind forcing. &lt;em&gt;Dynam. Atmos. Oceans.&lt;/em&gt;, 12, 170-191&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Song, H.&lt;/strong&gt;, I. Hoteit, B. D. Cornuelle and A. C. Subramanian (2010), An adaptive approach to mitigate background covariance limitations in the ensemble Kalman filter. &lt;em&gt;Mon. Wea. Rev.&lt;/em&gt;, 138, 2825-2845&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>구자호</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/people/jahokoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/people/jahokoo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;연구분야&#34;&gt;연구분야&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Asian/Pacific air pollution and environment&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Polar atmospheric chemistry&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Regional and global distribution of atmospheric components&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;학력&#34;&gt;학력&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ph.d.&lt;/strong&gt; (2014) in Earth and Atmospheric Sciences, Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA, USA&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;M.Sc&lt;/strong&gt; (2008) in Atmospheric Sciences, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B.Sc&lt;/strong&gt; (2006) in Chemistry, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B.Sc&lt;/strong&gt; (2006) in Atmospheric Sciences, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;연구-경력&#34;&gt;연구 경력&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2016 - 2019 : Research Professor, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2014 - 2016 : Postdoctoral Fellow, University of Toronto, Toronto, Canada&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;논문&#34;&gt;논문&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Koo, J.-H., D. Lee, H. Bae, T. Lee, S. G. Na, S.-W. Yeh, J. Park, and M. J. Yeo (2024), Back-trajectory analyses for evaluating the transboundary transport effect to the aerosol pollution in South Korea, Environ. Pollut., 351, 124031, doi: 10.1016/j.envpol.2024.124031.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pan et al., and 40 co-authors (2024), East Asian summer monsoon delivers large abundances of very-short-lived organic chlorine substances to the lower stratosphere, PNAS, 121, e2318716121, doi:10.1073/pnas.2318716121.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yeo, M. J., and J.-H. Koo (2023), The estimation of urban air quality change in South Korea under the carbon net-zero scenario, Urban Clim., 49, 101438, doi:10.1016/j.uclim.2023.101438&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lee, H., T. Choi, S.-J. Kim, J. Bak, D. H. Ahn, N. A. Kramarova, S. S. Park, J. Kim, and J.-H. Koo (2022), Validation of satellite ozone profiles in austral spring using ozonesonde measurements in the Jang Bogo station, Antarctica, Environ. Res., 214, 114087, doi:10.1016/j.envres.2022.114087.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lee, T., S. Go, Y. G. Lee, S. S. Park, J. Park, and J.-H. Koo (2022), Temporal variability of surface air pollutants in megacities of South Korea, Front. Environ. Sci., 10, 915531, doi:10.3389/fenvs.2022.915531.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, S.-M., J.-H. Koo*, H. Lee, J. Mok, M. Choi, S. Go, S. Lee, Y. Cho, J. Hong, S. Seo, J. Lee, J.-W. Hong, and J. Kim (2021), Comparison of PM2.5 in Seoul, Korea estimated from the various ground-based and satellite AOD, Appl. Sci., 11, 10755, doi:10.3390/app112210755.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, S., S.-J. Park, H. Lee, D. H. Ahn, Y. Jung, T. Choi, B. Y. Lee, S. Kim, and J.-H. Koo* (2021), Evaluation of total ozone column from multiple satellite measurements in the Antarctic using the Brewer spectrophotometer, Remote Sens., 13, 1594, doi:10.3390/rs13081594.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Koo, J.-H.*, J. Lee, J. Kim, T. F. Eck, D. M. Giles, B. N. Holben, S. S. Park, M. Choi, N. Kim, J. Yoon, and Y. G. Lee (2021), Investigation of the relationship between the fine mode fraction and Ångström exponent: cases in Korea, Atmos. Res., 248, 105217, doi:10.1016/j.atmosres.2020.105217.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Koo, J.-H.*, J. Kim, Y. G. Lee, S. S. Park, S. Lee, H. Chong, Y. Cho, J. Kim, K. Choi, and T. Lee (2020), The implication of the air quality pattern in South Korea after the COVID-19 outbreak, Sci. Rep., 10, 22462, doi:10.1038/s41598-020-80429-4.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ahn, D. H., T. Choi, J. Kim, S. S. Park, Y. G. Lee, S.-J. Kim, and J.-H. Koo* (2019), Southern Hemisphere mid- and high-latitudinal AOD, CO, NO2, and HCHO: spatiotemporal patterns revealed by satellite observations, Progress in Earth and Planetary Science, 6, 34, doi:10.1186/s40645-019-0277-y.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lee, S., J. Kim, M. Choi, J. Hong, H. Lim, T. F. Eck, B. N. Holben, J.-Y. Ahn, J. Kim, and J.-H. Koo* (2019), Analysis of long-range transboundary transport (LRTT) effect on Korean aerosol pollution during the KORUS-AQ campaign, Atmos. Environ., 204, 53-67, doi:10.1016/j.atmosenv.2019.02.020.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Koo, J.-H.*, T. Choi, H. Lee, J. Kim, D. H. Ahn, J. Kim, Y.-H. Kim, C. Yoo, H. Hong, K.-J. Moon, and Y. G. Lee (2018), Total ozone characteristics associated with regional meteorology in West Antarctica, Atmos. Environ., 195, 78-88, doi:10.1016/j.atmosenv.2018.09.056.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lee, S., J. Hong, Y. Cho, M. Choi, J. Kim, S. S. Park, J.-Y. Ahn, S.-K. Kim, K.-J. Moon, T. F. Eck, B. N. Holben, and J.-H. Koo* (2018), Characteristics of classified aerosol types in the Korean peninsula during the MAPS-Seoul campaign, Aerosol Air Qual. Res., 18, 2195-2206, doi:10.4209/aaqr.2017.11.0474.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>송인선</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/people/insunsong/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/people/insunsong/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;연구분야&#34;&gt;연구분야&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;전지구 전층대기 모델링&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;고층대기&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;대기파동이론&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;학력&#34;&gt;학력&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ph.D.&lt;/strong&gt; (2005) Department of Atmospheric Sciences, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;M.S.&lt;/strong&gt; (1999) Department of Atmospheric Sciences, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B.S.&lt;/strong&gt; (1997) Department of Atmospheric Sciences, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;연구경력&#34;&gt;연구경력&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2021 - Current : Associate Professor, Yonsei University&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2015 - 2021    : Postdoctoral scientist, Korea Polar Research Institute&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2011 - 2015    : Korea Institute of Atmospheric Prediction Systems&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2007 - 2011    : Global Modeling and Assimilation Office, NASA GSFC&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2005 - 2007    : Institute of National Science, Yonsei University&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;담당과목&#34;&gt;담당과목&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;태양과기후&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;대기대순환개론&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;고층대기&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;기상응용수학&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;유체불안정성론&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;논문&#34;&gt;논문&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lee, W., &lt;strong&gt;Song, I. S.&lt;/strong&gt;, Shim, J. S., Liu, G., &amp;amp; Jee, G. (2024). The impact of lower atmosphere forecast uncertainties on WACCM‐X prediction of ionosphere‐thermosphere system during geomagnetic storms. Space Weather, 22(12), e2024SW004137.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yoo, J. H., Chun, H. Y., &amp;amp; &lt;strong&gt;Song, I. S.&lt;/strong&gt; (2024). In-Situ Generation of Planetary Waves in the Mesosphere by Zonally Asymmetric Gravity Wave Drag: A Revisit. Journal of the Atmospheric Sciences.(accepted)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lee, W., &lt;strong&gt;Song, I. S.&lt;/strong&gt;, Song, B. G., &amp;amp; Kim, Y. H. (2024). Quasi-10 d wave activity in the southern high-latitude mesosphere and lower thermosphere (MLT) region and its relation to large-scale instability and gravity wave drag. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics, 24(6), 3559-3575.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Song, B. G., &amp;amp; &lt;strong&gt;Song, I. S.&lt;/strong&gt; (2024). Coupling of long‐term trends of zonal winds between the mesopause and stratosphere in southern winter. Geophysical Research Letters, 51(4), e2023GL107014.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Shim, J. S., &lt;strong&gt;Song, I. S.&lt;/strong&gt;, Jee, G., Kwak, Y. S., Tsagouri, I., Goncharenko, L., &amp;hellip; &amp;amp; Habarulema, J. B. (2023). Validation of Ionospheric Specifications During Geomagnetic Storms: TEC and foF2 During the 2013 March Storm Event‐II. Space Weather, 21(5), e2022SW003388.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Song, B. G., Chun, H. Y., &lt;strong&gt;Song, I. S.&lt;/strong&gt;, Lee, C., Kim, J. H., &amp;amp; Jee, G. (2023). Long‐term characteristics of the meteor radar winds observed at King Sejong station, Antarctica. Journal of Geophysical Research: Atmospheres, 128(1), e2022JD037190.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lee, J., Claussen, M., Kim, J., Hong, J. W., &lt;strong&gt;Song, I. S.&lt;/strong&gt;, &amp;amp; Hong, J. (2022). Effect of nitrogen limitation and soil biophysics on Holocene greening of the Sahara. Climate of the Past, 18(2), 313-326.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kam, H., &lt;strong&gt;Song, I. S.&lt;/strong&gt;, Kim, J. H., Kim, Y. H., Song, B. G., Nakamura, T., &amp;hellip; &amp;amp; Kwak, Y. S. (2021). Mesospheric Short‐Period Gravity Waves in the Antarctic Peninsula Observed in All‐Sky Airglow Images and Their Possible Source Locations. Journal of Geophysical Research: Atmospheres, 126(24), e2021JD035842.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lee, J., Claussen, M., Kim, J., Hong, J. W., &lt;strong&gt;Song, I. S.&lt;/strong&gt;, &amp;amp; Hong, J. (2021). Effect of nitrogen limitation and soil processes on mid–Holocene greening of the Sahara. Climate of the Past Discussions, 2021, 1-25.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lee, W., &lt;strong&gt;Song, I. S.&lt;/strong&gt;, Kim, J. H., Kim, Y. H., Jeong, S. H., Eswaraiah, S., &amp;amp; Murphy, D. J. (2021). The observation and SD‐WACCM simulation of planetary wave activity in the middle atmosphere during the 2019 southern hemispheric sudden stratospheric warming. Journal of Geophysical Research: Space Physics, 126(6), e2020JA029094.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Song, B. G., &lt;strong&gt;Song, I. S.&lt;/strong&gt;, Chun, H. Y., Lee, C., Kam, H., Kim, Y. H., &amp;hellip; &amp;amp; Mitchell, N. J. (2021). Activities of small‐scale gravity waves in the upper mesosphere observed from meteor radar at King Sejong Station, Antarctica (62.22° S, 58.78° W) and their potential sources. Journal of Geophysical Research: Atmospheres, 126(10), e2021JD034528.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lee, J.-H., Jee, G., Kwak, Y.-S., Hwang, H., Seppala, A., &lt;b&gt;Song, I.-S.&lt;/b&gt;, Turunen, E., &amp;amp; Lee, D.-Y. (2021). Polar middle atmospheric responses to medium energy electron (MEE) using numerical model simulations. Atmosphere, 12(2), 133.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Song, B.-G., Chun, H.-Y., &amp;amp; &lt;b&gt;Song, I.-S.&lt;/b&gt; (2020). Role of gravity waves in a vortex-split sudden stratospheric warming in January 2009. Journal of the Atmospheric Sciences, 77(10), 3321-3342. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1175/JAS-D-20-0039.1&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1175/JAS-D-20-0039.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Song, I.-S.&lt;/b&gt;, Lee, C., Chun, H.-Y., Kim, J.-H., Jee, G., Song, B.-G., &amp;amp; Bacmeister, J. T. (2020): Propagation of gravity waves and its effects on pseudomomentum flux in a sudden stratospheric warming event. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics, 20(12), 7617-7644. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-20-7617-2020&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-20-7617-2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yoo, J.-H., &lt;b&gt;Song, I.-S.&lt;/b&gt;, Chun, H.-Y., &amp;amp; Song, B.-G. (2020). Inertia-gravity waves revealed in radiosonde data at Jang Bogo Station, Antarctica (74o37’S, 164o13’E): 2. Potential sources and their relation to inertia-gravity waves. Journal of Geophysical Research: Atmospheres, 125(7), e2019JD032260. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2019JD032260&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2019JD032260&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, Y.-H., Kiladis, G. N., Albers, J. R., Dias, J., Fujiwara, M., Anstey, J. A., Song, I.-S., Wright, C. J., Kawatani, Y., Lott, F., &amp;amp; Yoo, C. (2019). Comparison of equatorial wave activity in the tropical tropopause layer and stratosphere represented in reanalyses. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics, 19(15), 10027-10050. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-19-10027-2019&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-19-10027-2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yoo, J.-H., Choi, T., Chun, H.-Y., Kim, Y.-H., &lt;b&gt;Song, I.-S.&lt;/b&gt;, &amp;amp; Song, B.-G. (2018). Inertia-gravity waves revealed in radiosonde data at Jang Bogo Station, Antarctica (74o37’S, 164o13’E): 1. Characteristics, energy and momentum Flux. Journal of Geophysical Research: Atmospheres, 123(23), 13305-13331. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2018JD029164&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2018JD029164&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lee, J.-H., Jee, G., Kwak, Y.-S., Hong, S.-B., Hwang, H.~J., &lt;b&gt;Song, I.-S.&lt;/b&gt;, Lee, Y.-S., Turunen, E., &amp;amp; Lee, D.-Y. (2018). Responses of nitrogen oxide to high-speed solar wind stream in the polar middle atmosphere. Journal of Geophysical Research: Space Physics, 123(11), 9788-9801. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2017JA025161&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2017JA025161&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lee, C., Kim, J.-H., Jee, G., &amp;amp; &lt;b&gt;Song, I.-S.&lt;/b&gt; (2018). Meteor echo height ceiling effect and the mesospheric temperature estimation from meteor radar observation. Annales Geophysicae, 36(5), 1267-1274. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5194/angeo-36-1267-2018&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5194/angeo-36-1267-2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Song, I.-S.&lt;/b&gt;, Chun, H.-Y., Jee, G., Kim, S.-Y., Kim, J., Kim, Y.-H., &amp;amp; Taylor, M. A. (2018). Dynamic initialization for whole-atmospheric global modeling. Journal of Advances in Modeling Earth Systems, 10(9), 2096-2120. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2017MS001213&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2017MS001213&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Song, I.-S.&lt;/b&gt;, Byun, U.-Y., Hong, J., &amp;amp; Park, S.-H. (2018). Domain-size and top-height dependence in regional predictions for the Northeast Asia in spring. Atmospheric Science Letters, 19(1), e799. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/asl.799&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/asl.799&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lee, C., Jee, G., Wu, Q., Shim, J. S., Murphy, D., &lt;b&gt;Song, I.-S.&lt;/b&gt;, Kwon, H.-J., Kim, J.-H., &amp;amp; Kim, Y. H. (2017). Polar thermospheric winds and temperature observed by Fabry-Perot interferometer at Jang Bogo Station, Antarctica. Journal of Geophysical Research: Space Physics, 122(9), 9685-9695. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/2017JA024408&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/2017JA024408&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Song, I.-S.&lt;/b&gt;, Lee, C., Kim, J.-H., Jee, G., Kim, Y.-H., Choi, H.-J., Chun, H.-Y., &amp;amp; Kim, Y. H. (2017). Meteor radar observations of vertically propagating low-frequency inertia-gravity waves near the southern polar mesopause region. Journal of Geophysical Research: Space Physics, 122(4), 4777-4800. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/2016JA022978&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/2016JA022978&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kam, H., Jee, G., Kim, Y., Ham, Y.-B., &amp;amp; &lt;b&gt;Song, I.-S.&lt;/b&gt; (2017). Statistical analysis of mesospheric gravity waves over King Sejong Station, Antarctica (62.2oS, 58.8oW). Journal of Atmospheric and Solar-Terrestrial Physics, 155, 86-94, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jastp.2017.02.006&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jastp.2017.02.006&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lee, C., Kim, J.-H., Jee, G., Lee, W., &lt;b&gt;Song, I.-S.&lt;/b&gt;, &amp;amp; Kim, Y. H. (2016). New method of estimating temperatures near the mesopause region using meteor radar observations. Geophysical Research Letters, 43(20), 10580-10585. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/2016GL071082&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/2016GL071082&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, Y.-H., Chun, H.-Y., Park, S.-H., &lt;b&gt;Song, I.-S.&lt;/b&gt;, &amp;amp; Choi, H.-J. (2016). Characteristics of gravity waves generated in the jet-front system in a baroclinic instability simulation. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics, 16(8), 4799-4815. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-16-4799-2016&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-16-4799-2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>유영희</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/people/yhryu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/people/yhryu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;연구분야&#34;&gt;연구분야&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Boundary layer meteorology and turbulence&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Air quality modeling and Air pollutants/meteorology/climate interactions&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Urban meteorology modeling&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Land/atmosphere interactions&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Environmental big data&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;학력&#34;&gt;학력&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ph.D. (2012) in Atmospheric Sciences, Seoul National University&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;B.S.  (2006) in Physics and in Atmospheric Sciences (dual majors), Seoul National University&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;연구경력&#34;&gt;연구경력&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2023.03 - present : Associate Professor, Yonsei University&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2022.09 - 2023.02 : Associate Professor, Kongju National University&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2020 - 2022 : Research Associate Professor, POSTECH&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2015 - 2019 : Postdoctoral Researcher/Visiting Scientist, National Center for Atmospheric Research (NCAR)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2013 - 2015 : Postdoctoral Research Associate, Princeton University&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2012 - 2013 : Postdoctoral Fellow, Seoul National University&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;논문&#34;&gt;논문&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ryu, Y.-H., and S.-K. Min, 2022: Greenhouse warming and anthropogenic aerosols synergistically reduce springtime rainfall in low-latitude East Asia, npj Climate and Atmospheric Science, 5, 69. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41612-022-00295-x&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41612-022-00295-x&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ryu, Y.-H., S.-K. Min, and C. Knote, 2022: Contrasting roles of clouds as a sink and source of aerosols: A quantitative assessment using WRF-Chem over East Asia, Atmospheric Environment, 277, 119073. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.atmosenv.2022.119073&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.atmosenv.2022.119073&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ryu, Y.-H. and S.-K. Min, 2022: Improving wet and dry deposition of aerosols in WRF-Chem: Updates to below-cloud scavenging and coarse-particle dry deposition, Journal of Advances in Modeling Earth Systems, 14, e2021MS002792. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2021MS002792&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2021MS002792&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ryu, Y.-H., S.-K. Min, and C. Knote, 2022: Role of upwind precipitation in transboundary pollution and secondary aerosol formation: A case study during the KORUS-AQ field campaign, Journal of Applied Meteorology and Climatology, 61, 159–174. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1175/JAMC-D-21-0162.1&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1175/JAMC-D-21-0162.1&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ryu, Y.-H., S.-K. Min, and A. Hodzic, 2021: Recent decreasing trends in surface PM2.5 over East Asia in the winter-spring season: Different responses to emissions and meteorology between upwind and downwind regions. Aerosol and Air Quality Research, 21, 200654. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.4209/aaqr.200654&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.4209/aaqr.200654&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Wang, C., Z.-H. Wang, and Y.-H. Ryu, 2021: A single-layer urban canopy model with transmissive radiation exchange between trees and street canyons. Building and Environment, 191, 107593. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.buildenv.2021.107593&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.buildenv.2021.107593&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ryu, Y.-H., S.-K. Min, 2021: Long-term evaluation of atmospheric composition reanalyses from CAMS, TCR-2, and MERRA-2 over South Korea: Insights into applications, implications, and limitations. Atmospheric Environment, 246, 118062. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.atmosenv.2020.118062&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.atmosenv.2020.118062&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ryu, Y.-H., S.-K. Min, 2020: What matters in public perception and awareness of air quality? Quantitative assessment using internet search volume data. Environmental Research Letters, 15, 0940b4. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/ab9fb0&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/ab9fb0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ryu, Y.-H., A. Hodzic, G. Descombes, M. Hu, and J. Barre, 2019: Towards a better regional ozone forecast over CONUS using rapid data assimilation of clouds and meteorology in WRF-Chem, Journal of Geophysical Research–Atmospheres, 124, 13576–13592.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2019JD031232&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2019JD031232&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ryu, Y.-H., A. Hodzic, J. Barre, G. Descombes, and P. Minnis, 2018: Quantifying errors in surface ozone predictions associated with clouds over CONUS: A WRF-Chem modeling study using satellite cloud retrievals, Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics, 18, 7509–7525. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-18-7509-2018&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-18-7509-2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ryu, Y.-H., A. Hodzic, G. Descombes, S. Hall, P. Minnis, D. Spangenberg, K. Ullmann, and S. Madronich, 2017: Improved modeling of cloudy-sky actinic flux using satellite cloud retrievals. Geophysical Research Letters, 44, 1592–1600.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/2016GL071892&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/2016GL071892&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ryu, Y.-H., E. Bou-Zeid, Z. Wang, and J. A. Smith, 2016: Realistic representation of trees in an urban canopy model. Boundary-Layer Meteorology, 159, 193–220. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10546-015-0120-y&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10546-015-0120-y&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ryu, Y.-H., J. A. Smith, E. Bou-Zeid, and M. L. Baeck, 2016: The influence of land-surface heterogeneities on heavy convective rainfall in the Washington-Baltimore metropolitan area. Monthly Weather Review, 144, 553–573. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1175/MWR-D-15-0192.1&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1175/MWR-D-15-0192.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ryu, Y.-H., J.-J. Baik, and S.-H. Lee, 2013: Effects of anthropogenic heat on ozone air quality in a megacity. Atmospheric Environment, 80, 20−30. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.atmosenv.2013.07.053&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.atmosenv.2013.07.053&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ryu, Y.-H., J.-J. Baik, K.-H. Kwak, S. Kim, and N. Moon, 2013: Impacts of urban land-surface forcing on ozone air quality in the Seoul metropolitan area. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics, 13, 2177−2194. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-13-2177-2013&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-13-2177-2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ryu, Y.-H., and J.-J. Baik, 2012: Quantitative analysis of factors contributing to urban heat island intensity. Journal of Applied Meteorology and Climatology, 51, 842−854. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1175/JAMC-D-11-098.1&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1175/JAMC-D-11-098.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ryu, Y.-H., J.-J. Baik, and S.-H. Lee, 2011: A new single-layer urban canopy model for use in mesoscale atmospheric models. Journal of Applied Meteorology and Climatology, 50, 1773−1794. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1175/2011JAMC2665.1&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1175/2011JAMC2665.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
