<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Researchers on Department of Atmospheric Sciences, Yonsei University</title>
    <link>http://atmos.yonsei.ac.kr/eng/teams/researchers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Researchers on Department of Atmospheric Sciences, Yonsei University</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 13:39:46 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://atmos.yonsei.ac.kr/eng/teams/researchers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ja-Ho Koo</title>
      <link>http://atmos.yonsei.ac.kr/eng/people/jahokoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://atmos.yonsei.ac.kr/eng/people/jahokoo/</guid>
      <description>Research interests  Asian/Pacific air pollution and environment Polar atmospheric chemistry Regional and global distribution of atmospheric components  Education  Ph.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seung-On Hwang</title>
      <link>http://atmos.yonsei.ac.kr/eng/people/seungonhwang/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://atmos.yonsei.ac.kr/eng/people/seungonhwang/</guid>
      <description>Research interests  Data assimilation Numerical weather prediction modeling  Education  Ph.d. (2011) in Atmospheric Science, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Si-Wan Kim</title>
      <link>http://atmos.yonsei.ac.kr/eng/people/siwankim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://atmos.yonsei.ac.kr/eng/people/siwankim/</guid>
      <description>Research interests  Air quality (tropospheric ozone and aerosols) Atmospheric composition Atmospheric chemistry and transport models Convection and boundary layer dynamics Mesoscale numerical models Utilization of satellite trace gas and aerosol retrievals for air quality and climate research  Education  Ph.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Woo-Jin Lee</title>
      <link>http://atmos.yonsei.ac.kr/eng/people/woojinlee/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://atmos.yonsei.ac.kr/eng/people/woojinlee/</guid>
      <description>Research interests  numerical weather prediction, weather forecast dynamic meteorology  Education  Ph.d. (1994) in Meteorology, University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, IL, USA M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ashley Brereton</title>
      <link>http://atmos.yonsei.ac.kr/eng/people/ashleybrereton/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://atmos.yonsei.ac.kr/eng/people/ashleybrereton/</guid>
      <description>Research interests Large-eddy simulation Ocean mixed layer turbulence Plankton population dynamics Bio-physical interactions Ocean model development Tidal turbulence
Education  Ph.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ji-Won Kim</title>
      <link>http://atmos.yonsei.ac.kr/eng/people/jiwonkim/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://atmos.yonsei.ac.kr/eng/people/jiwonkim/</guid>
      <description>Research interests  ENSO teleconnection ENSO dynamics  Education  Ph.d. (2017) in Atmospheric Sciences, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Myungje Choi</title>
      <link>http://atmos.yonsei.ac.kr/eng/people/myungjechoi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://atmos.yonsei.ac.kr/eng/people/myungjechoi/</guid>
      <description>Research interests  Retrieval of aerosol optical properties using a multi-channel ocean color sensor onboard a geostationary satellite Validation and uncertainty estimation of aerosol optical properties from geostationary satellite using ground-based and other satellite-based observations Analysis of aerosol optical properties diurnal variation and long-range transport using a geostationary satellite Data assimilation of geostationary satellite aerosol optical properties with air quality modeling Relevance between satellite-retrieved aerosol optical properties and ground in-situ particulate matter  Education  Ph.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sehyun Kim</title>
      <link>http://atmos.yonsei.ac.kr/eng/people/sehyunkim/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://atmos.yonsei.ac.kr/eng/people/sehyunkim/</guid>
      <description>Research interests  Data assimilation Ensemble forecast  Education  Ph.d. (2017) in Meteorology, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea M.Sc (2012) in Meteorology, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Silvio Kalisch</title>
      <link>http://atmos.yonsei.ac.kr/eng/people/silviokalisch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://atmos.yonsei.ac.kr/eng/people/silviokalisch/</guid>
      <description>Research interests  Middle Atmosphere dynamics Gravity Waves Tropical atmosphere (Madden-Julian Oscillation)  Education  Dr. rer. nat. (Ph.d.) (2014) in Physics, University of Wuppertal / Research Center Juelich, Germany Diplom (M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yuri Lee</title>
      <link>http://atmos.yonsei.ac.kr/eng/people/yurilee/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://atmos.yonsei.ac.kr/eng/people/yurilee/</guid>
      <description>Research interests  Remote sensing for precipitation estimation  Education  Ph.d. (2017) in Atmospheric Sciences, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea M.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>