<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Staff on 연세대학교 대기과학과</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/teams/staff/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Staff on 연세대학교 대기과학과</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>ko</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 01:00:00 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/teams/staff/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>박정규</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/people/jkpark/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/people/jkpark/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;연구분야&#34;&gt;연구분야&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Climate prediction and analysis&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Asian monsoon and drought&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Climate change science and adaptation&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Urban climate and air quality&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;학력&#34;&gt;학력&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ph.D. (1987) Department of Atmospheric Sciences, University of Missouri-Columbia, MO, USA&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;M.S. (1980) Department of Astronomy and Meteorology, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;B.S. (1978) Department of Astronomy and Meteorology, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;경력&#34;&gt;경력&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sept 2020 -present &#x9;Professor extraordinary, Department of Atmospheric sciences, Yonsei University&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mar 2013 – Aug 2020&#x9;Director, Regional Office for Asia and the South-West Pacific, World Meteorological Organization (WMO)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mar 2009 - Feb 2013&#x9;Director-General, Planning &amp;amp; Coordination Bureau, Met Industry &amp;amp; Information and Telecommunication Bureau, Climate Science Bureau, Korea Meteorological Administration&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Apr 2008 - Feb 2009&#x9;Director-General, Metropolitan Air Quality Management Office, Ministry of Environment&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sep 2005 - Apr 2008&#x9;Executive Director, APEC Climate Center&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mar 1987-Dec 1996&#x9;Senior scientist, Goddard Space Flight Center (GSFC),US National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;담당-과목&#34;&gt;담당 과목&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;General circulation&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Climate dynamics&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;논문&#34;&gt;논문&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Wang, B, JY Lee, IS. Kang, J. Shukla, JS. Kug, A. Kumar, J. Schemm, JJ. Luo, T. Yamagata and CK. Park, 2008: How accurately do coupled climate models predict the leading modes of Asian-Australian monsoon interannual variability? Climate Dynamics, 30, 605-619&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kang, H., K.-H. An, C.-K. Park, A. L. S. Solis, and K. Stitthichivapak, 2007:  Multimodel output statistical downscaling prediction of precipitation in the Philippines and Thailand, Geophys. Res. Lett., vol. 34.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kang, H. and C.-K. Park, 2007: Error analysis of dynamical seasonal predictions of summer precipitation over the East Asian-western Pacific region, Geophys. Res. Lett., 34, L13706, doi:10.1029/2007GL029392.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kryjov, V. N. and C.-K. Park, 2007: Solar modulation of the El-Niño/Southern Oscillation impact on the Northern Hemisphere annular mode, Geophys. Res. Lett., 34, L10701, doi:10.1029/2006GL028015.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kar, Sarat C., Anahit hovsepyan and C. K. Park, 2006: Economic Values of the APCN Multi-Model Ensemble Categorical Seasonal Prediction. Meteorology. Appl. 13, 267-277.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ha, K.-J., K.-S. Yun, J.-G. Jhun and C.-K. Park, 2005: Definition of Onset/Retreat and Intensity of Changma during the Boreal Summer Monsoon Season. J. Korea Meteorological Society, 41(6), 927-942.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lee, E.-J., J.-G. Jhun, and C.-K. Park, 2005: Remote connection of the northeast Asian summer rainfall variation revealed by a newly defined monsoon index. J. Climate. 18, 4381-4393&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Zhu, C., W.-S. Lee, H. Kang, and C.-K. Park, 2005: A proper monsoon index for seasonal and interannual variations of the East Asian Monsoon. Geophysical Research Letters. 32, L02811, doi:10.1029/2004GL021295&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, M.-K., I.-S. Kang, C.-K. Park and K.-M. Kim, 2004: Superensemble prediction of regional precipitation over Korea, International Journal of Climatology, 24(6), 777-790&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kang, I.-S, J.-Y. Lee, and C.K. Park, 2004: Potential predictability of summer mean precipitation in a dynamical season prediction system with systematic error correction. J. Climate, 17, 834-844.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ahn, J.-B., C.-K. Park and E.-S. Im, 2002: Reproduction of Regional Scale Surface air Temperature by Estimating Systematic Bias of Mesoscale Numerical Model, J. Korea Meteorological Society, 38(1), 69-80.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kang, I.-S., K. Jin, B. Wang, K.-M. Lau, J. Shukla, V. Krishnamurthy, S. D. Schubert, D. E. Wailser, W. F. Stern, A. Kitoh, G. A. Meehl, M. Kanamitsu, V. Y. Galin, V. Satyan, C.-K. Park, Y. Liu, 2002: Intercomparison of the climatological variations of Asian summer monsoon precipitation simulated by 10 GCMs. Climate Dynamics, 19, 383-395.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Park, C.-K., J.-D. Hwang and Y. Chun, 2001: The Expressions Related to Rain fall Recorded in the Chosun_Wangjo-Sillok. J. Korea Meteorological Society, 37(4), 433-441.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Min, S.-K., C.-K. Park, 2001: Application of Nonlinear Barotropic Primitive Equation Model to Medium Range Weather Forecast. J. Korea Metoerological Society, 37(2), 129-142.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hwang, J.-D. and C.-K. Park, 2000: Characteristics of Circulation Pattern over East Asia Associated with Heavy Rainfall Events in Korea during the Summer 1999, J. Korea Meteorological Society, 36(5), 573-582.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Park, C.-K., and S.D. Schubert,1997: On the nature of the 1994 East Asian summer drought. J. Climate, 10, 1056-1070.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Slingo, J.M., C.-K. Park, and others, 1996: Intraseasonal oscillations in 15 atmospheric general circulation models: results from an AMIP diagnostic subproject. Climate Dynamics, 12, 325-357&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Park, C.-K., M. Suarez, and S.D. Schubert, 1995: Response of zonally asymmetric flow to time-dependent tropical heating. J. Atmos. Sci., 52, 3738-3756.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Schubert, S.D., M Suarez, C.-K. Park, and S. Moorthi, 1993: GCM Simulations of Intraseasonal variability in the Pacific/North American Region. J. Atmos. Sci., 50, 1991-2007.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Park, C.-K., and S.D. Schubert, 1993: Remotely-forced intraseasonal oscillations over the tropical Atlantic. J. Atmos. Sci., 50, 89-103.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Schubert, S.D. C.-Y. Wu, J. Zero, J.-K. Schemm, C.-K. Park, and M Suarez, 1992: Monthly means of selected climate variables for 1985-89. NASA Memorandum 104565, 360pp.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kung, E.C., W. Min, J. Susskind, and C.-K. Park, 1992: An analysis of simulated summer blocking episodes. Q. J. Royal Meteor. Soc., 118,&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Schubert, S.D. and C.-K. Park, 1991: Low-frequency intraseasonal tropical-extratropical interactions. J. Atmos. Sci., 48, 629-650.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kung, E.C., C.C. Dacamara, W.E. Baker, J. Susskind, and C.-K. Park, 1990: Simulations of winter blocking episodes using observed sea surface temperatures. Q. J. Royal Meteor. Soc., 116, 1053-1070.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Schubert, S.D.R.W. Higgins, C.-K. Park, S. Moorthi, and M Suarez, 1990: An atlas of ECMWF analyses (1980-87), Part II - second moment quantities. NASA Technical Memorandum 100762, 286pp.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Schubert, S.D.C.-K. Park, R.W. Higgins, S. Moorthi, and M Suarez, 1990: An atlas of ECMWF analyses (1980-87), Part I - first moment quantities. NASA Technical Memorandum 100747, 273pp.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Park, C.-K., D.M. Straus, K-M. Lau, and S.D. Schubert, 1990: An intercomparison of intraseasonal variability in general circulation models and observations. NASA Technical Memorandum 100764,121pp.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Park, C.-K., D.M. Straus, and K-M. Lau, 1990: An evaluation of the structure of tropical intraseasonal oscillations in three general circulation models. J. Meteor. Society of Japan, 68, 403-417.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Park, C.-K. and E. C. Kung, 1988: Principal components of the North American summer temperature field and the antecedent oceanic and conditions of the Northern Hemisphere. J. Meteor. Society Japan, 66, 677-690.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>여민주</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/people/minjuyeo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 08:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/people/minjuyeo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;연구분야&#34;&gt;연구분야&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Factors affecting air quality&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;학력&#34;&gt;학력&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ph.D.&lt;/strong&gt; (2015) in Environmental Science and Engineering, Ewha Womans University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;M.Sc&lt;/strong&gt; (2005) in Environmental Science and Engineering, Ewha Womans University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B.Sc&lt;/strong&gt; (2003) in Environmental Science and Engineering, Ewha Womans University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;연구경력&#34;&gt;연구경력&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2022 - present: Research Professor, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2020 - present: Lecturer, Seoul National University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2017 - 2022: Research Professor, Ewha Womans University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2017: Lecturer, Korea Military Academy, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2015 - 2017: Postdoctoral researcher, Ewha Womans University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2011 - 2012: Lecturer, Ewha Womans University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2005 - 2008: Senior Researcher, Eco-Frontier, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;논문&#34;&gt;논문&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yeo, M.J., Kim, Y.P. (2022) Long-term trends and affecting factors in the concentrations of criteria air pollutants in South Korea. Journal of Environmental Management, 317, 115458. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2022.115458&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2022.115458&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yeo, M.J., Kim, Y.P., Jung, C.H. (2022) Effects of SOx Emission on SO2 concentration by district in Korea. Journal of Korean Society for Atmospheric Environment, 38(2), 269-282 (in Korean with English abstract). &lt;a href=&#34;http://doi.org/10.5572/KOSAE.2022.38.2.269&#34;&gt;http://doi.org/10.5572/KOSAE.2022.38.2.269&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lee, Y.W., Kim, Y.P., Yeo, M.J. (2021) Estimation of air pollutant emissions from heavy industry sector in North Korea, Particle and Aerosol Research, 17(4), 133-148 (in Korean with English abstract). &lt;a href=&#34;http://doi.org/10.11629/jpaar.2021.17.4.133&#34;&gt;http://doi.org/10.11629/jpaar.2021.17.4.133&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yeo, M.J., Kim, Y.P. (2021) Long-term trends of surface ozone in Korea, Journal of Cleaner Production, 294, 125352. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2020.125352&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2020.125352&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yeo, M.J., Kim, Y.P. (2020) Long-term trend of sulfur dioxide concentration by district in Korea. Journal of Korean Society for Atmospheric Environment, 36(6), 742-756 (in Korean with English abstract). &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5572/KOSAE.2020.36.6.742&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5572/KOSAE.2020.36.6.742&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yeo, M.J., Seo, J., Kim, Y.P. (2019) Temporal and spatial characteristics of visibility in North Korea. Journal of Korean Society for Atmospheric Environment, 35(6), 726–740  (in Korean with English abstract). &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5572/KOSAE.2019.35.6.726&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5572/KOSAE.2019.35.6.726&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yeo, M.J., Im, Y.S., Yoo, S.S., Jeon, E.M., Kim, Y.P. (2019) Long-term trend of PM2.5 Concentration in Seoul. Journal of Korean Society for Atmospheric Environment, 35(4), 438-450. (in Korean with English abstract), &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5572/KOSAE.2019.35.4.438&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5572/KOSAE.2019.35.4.438&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yeo, M.J., Kim, Y.P. (2019) Trends of the PM2.5 concentrations and high PM2.5 concentration cases by region in Korea. Particle and Aerosol Research. 15(2), 45-56 (in Korean with English abstract). &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.11629/jpaar.2019.15.2.045&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.11629/jpaar.2019.15.2.045&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yeo, M.J., Kim, Y.P. (2019) The State of the air quality and measures for improving it in North Korea. Journal of Korean Society for Atmospheric Environment, 35(3), 318-335 (in Korean with English abstract). &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5572/KOSAE.2019.35.3.318&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5572/KOSAE.2019.35.3.318&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yeo, M.J., Kim, Y.P. (2019) Trends of the PM10 concentrations and high PM10 concentration cases in Korea. Journal of Korean Society for Atmospheric Environment, 35(2), 249-264 (in Korean with English abstract). &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5572/KOSAE.2019.35.2.249&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5572/KOSAE.2019.35.2.249&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yeo, M.J., Kim, Y.P. (2019) Estimation of the carbon dioxide emission change due to the change of the meat consumption behavior in North Korea. Journal of Korean Society for Atmospheric Environment, 35(1), 1-15 (in Korean with English abstract). &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5572/KOSAE.2019.35.1.001&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5572/KOSAE.2019.35.1.001&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Volodya, E., Yeo, M.J., Kim, Y.P. (2018) Trends of ecological footprints and policy direction for sustainable development in Mongolia: A case study. Sustainability, 10(11), 4026. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/su10114026&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/su10114026&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yeo, M.J., Kim, Y.P. (2018) Electricity supply trend and operating statuses of coal-fired power plants in North Korea using the facility-specific data produced by North Korea: characterization and recommendations. Air Quality, Atmosphere &amp;amp; Health, 11, 979-992. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s11869-018-0601-5&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s11869-018-0601-5&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>박민수</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/people/minsupark/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/people/minsupark/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;연구분야&#34;&gt;연구분야&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Measurement of physical characteristics of aerosol and CCN&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;학력&#34;&gt;학력&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B.Sc&lt;/strong&gt; (2012) in Atmospheric Sciences, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ph.D&lt;/strong&gt; (2018) in Cloud Physics, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;수상내역&#34;&gt;수상내역&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;논문&#34;&gt;논문&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, J. H., Park, M.-S., Shim, S., and Yum, S. S., (2012), On the contrast of aerosol size distribution and cloud condensation nuclei number concentrations between the east and the west of the Korean Peninsula. Atmosphere, 22, 87-96 (in Korean).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, J. H., Yum, S. S., Shim, S., Kim, W. J., Park, M., Kim, J.-H., Kim, M.-H., Yoon, S.-C. (2014), On the submicron aerosol distributions and CCN number concentrations in and around the Korean Peninsula. Atmos. Chem. Phys., 14, 8763–8779.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Park, M., Yum, S. S., Kim, J. H. (2015), Characteristics of submicron aerosol number size distribution and new particle formation events measured in Seoul, Korea, during 2004–2012. Asia-Pacific J. Atmos. Sci., 51, 1–10.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Park, M., Yum, S. S., Kim, N., Cha, J. W., Ryoo, S.-B. (2016), Characteristics of Aerosol and Cloud Condensation Nuclei Concentrations Measured over the Yellow Sea on a Meteorological Research Vessel, GISANG 1. Atmosphere, 26, 243–256 (in Korean).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, N., Park, M., Yum, S. S., Park, J. S., Song, I. H., Shin, H. J., Ahn, J. Y., Kwak, K.-H., Kim, H., Bae, G.-N. (2017), Hygroscopic properties of urban aerosols and their cloud condensation nuclei activities measured in Seoul during the MAPS-Seoul campaign. Atmos. Environ., 153, 217–232.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Schmale, J., Henning, S., Henzing, B., Keskinen, H., Sellegri, K., Ovadnevaite, J., Bougiatioti, A., Kalivitis, N., Stavroulas, I., Jefferson, A., Park, M., Schlag, P., Kristensson, A., Iwamoto, Y., Pringle, K., Reddington, C., Aalto, P., Äijälä, M., Baltensperger, U., Bialek, J., Birmili, W., Bukowiecki, N., Ehn, M., Fjæraa, A. M., Fiebig, M., Frank, G., Fröhlich, R., Frumau, A., Furuya, M., Hammer, E., Heikkinen, L., Herrmann, E., Holzinger, R., Hyono, H., Kanakidou, M., Kiendler, Scharr, A., Kinouchi, K., Kos, G., Kulmala, M., Mihalopoulos, N., Motos, G., Nenes, A., O’Dowd, C., Paramonov, M., Petäjä, T., Picard, D., Poulain, L., Prévôt, A. S. H., Slowik, J., Sonntag, A., Swietlicki, E., Svenningsson, B., Tsurumaru, H., Wiedensohler, A., Wittbom, C., Ogren, J. A., Matsuki, A., Yum, S. S., Myhre, C. L., Carslaw, K., Stratmann, F., Gysel, M. (2017), Collocated observations of cloud condensation nuclei, particle size distributions, and chemical composition, Scientific Data, 4, 170003.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Schmale, J., Henning, S., Decesari, S., Henzing, B., Keskinen, H., Paramonov, M., Sellegri, K., Ovadnevaite, J., Pöhlker, M. L., Brito, J., Bougiatioti, A., Kristensson, A., Kalivitis, N., Stavroulas, I., Carbone, S., Jefferson, A., Park, M., Schlag, P., Iwamoto, Y., Aalto, P., Äijälä, M., Bukowiecki, N., Ehn, M., Frank, G., Fröhlich, R., Frumau, A., Herrmann, E., Herrmann, H., Holzinger, R., Kos, G., Kulmala, M., Mihalopoulos, N., Nenes, A., O&amp;rsquo;Dowd, C., Petäjä, T., Picard, D., Pöhlker, C., Pöschl, U., Poulain, L., Prévôt, A. S. H., Swietlicki, E., Andreae, M. O., Artaxo, P., Wiedensohler, A., Ogren, J., Matsuki, A., Yum, S. S., Stratmann, F., Baltensperger, U., Gysel, M. 2018. Long-term cloud condensation nuclei number concentration, particle number size distribution, and chemical composition measurements at regionally representative observatories, Atmos. Chem. Phys..&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>신우주</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/people/ujushin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/people/ujushin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;연구분야&#34;&gt;연구분야&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mesoscale convective system&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Heavy precipitation systems over the Korean peninsula&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;학력&#34;&gt;학력&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ph.D.&lt;/strong&gt; (2019) in Atmospheric Sciences, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;M.Sc&lt;/strong&gt; (2010) in Atmospheric Sciences, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B.Sc&lt;/strong&gt; (2008) in Atmospheric Sciences, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;수상내역&#34;&gt;수상내역&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;논문&#34;&gt;논문&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Shin, U&lt;/b&gt;, S.-H. Park, J.-S. Park, J.-H. Koo, C. Yoo, S. Kim, and J.-B. Lee (2021), Predictability of PM2.5 in Seoul based on atmospheric blocking forecasts using the NCEP global forecast system, Atmospheric Environment, 246, 118141, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.atmosenv.2020.118141&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.atmosenv.2020.118141&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lee, T.-Y., &lt;b&gt;U. Shin&lt;/b&gt;, and S.-H. Park (2020), Atmospheric Structure for Convective Development in the Events of Cloud Clusters over the Korean Peninsula, Asia-Pacific J. Atmos. Sci., &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s13143-020-00211-4&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s13143-020-00211-4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Shin, U.&lt;/b&gt;, T.-Y. Lee, and S.-H. Park (2019), Environment and processes for heavy rainfall in the early morning over the Korean peninsula during episodes of cloud clusters associated with mesoscale troughs. J. Meteor. Soc. Japan, 97, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.2151/jmsj.2019-036&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.2151/jmsj.2019-036&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Shin, U.&lt;/b&gt; and T.-Y. Lee (2015), Origin, Evolution, Structure of Meso-α-scale Lows Associated with Cloud Clusters and Heavy Rainfall over the Korean Peninsula. Asia-Pacific J. Atmos. Sci., 51(3), 259−274, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s13143-015-0076-3&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s13143-015-0076-3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>이서영</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/people/seoyounglee/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/people/seoyounglee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;연구분야&#34;&gt;연구분야&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Retrieval of aerosols and trace gases from satellite or airborne based remote sensing measurements&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Estimation of the long-range transport of aerosols&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Radiative transfer model&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;학력&#34;&gt;학력&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B.Sc&lt;/strong&gt; (2015) in Atmospheric Sciences, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;수상내역&#34;&gt;수상내역&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Group Achievement Award, 2017.08, NASA &amp;ldquo;KORUS-AQ: An International Cooperative Air Quality Field Study in Korea&amp;rdquo; project&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;논문&#34;&gt;논문&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lee, S., Kim, M., Kim, S. Y., Lee, D. W., Lee, H., Kim, J., &amp;hellip; &amp;amp; Liu, Y. (2021). Assessment of long-range transboundary aerosols in Seoul, South Korea from Geostationary Ocean Color Imager (GOCI) and ground-based observations. Environmental Pollution, 269, 115924.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Koo, J. H., Kim, J., Lee, Y. G., Park, S. S., Lee, S., Chong, H., &amp;hellip; &amp;amp; Lee, T. (2020). The implication of the air quality pattern in South Korea after the COVID-19 outbreak. Scientific reports, 10(1), 1-11.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Choi, M., Lim, H., Kim, J., Lee, S., Eck, T. F., Holben, B. N., &amp;hellip; &amp;amp; Liu, H. (2019). Validation, comparison, and integration of GOCI, AHI, MODIS, MISR, and VIIRS aerosol optical depth over East Asia during the 2016 KORUS-AQ campaign. Atmospheric Measurement Techniques, 12(8), 4619-4641.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lee, S., Kim, J., Choi, M., Hong, J., Lim, H., Eck, T. F., &amp;hellip; &amp;amp; Koo, J. H. (2019). Analysis of long-range transboundary transport (LRTT) effect on Korean aerosol pollution during the KORUS-AQ campaign. Atmospheric Environment, 204, 53-67.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lee, S., Hong, J., Cho, Y., Choi, M., Kim, J., Park, S. S., &amp;hellip; &amp;amp; Koo, J. H. (2018). Characteristics of classified aerosol types in south korea during the maps-seoul campaign. Aerosol and Air Quality Research, 18(9), 2195-2206.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, S. W., Natraj, V., Lee, S., Kwon, H. A., Park, R., Gouw, J. D., &amp;hellip; &amp;amp; Warneke, C. (2018). Impact of high-resolution a priori profiles on satellite-based formaldehyde retrievals. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics, 18(10), 7639-7655.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lee, S., Choi, M., Kim, J., Kim, M., and Lim, H.: Retrieval of Aerosol Optical Depth with High Spatial Resolution using GOCI Data, Korean Journal of Remote Sensing, Vol.33, No.6-1, 2017.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>이유리</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/people/yurilee/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/people/yurilee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;연구분야&#34;&gt;연구분야&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Remote sensing for precipitation estimation&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;학력&#34;&gt;학력&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ph.d.&lt;/strong&gt;  (2017) in Atmospheric Sciences, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;M.Sc&lt;/strong&gt;  (2012) in Earth Science Education, Ewha Womans University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B.Sc&lt;/strong&gt;  (2010) in Earth Science Education, Ewha Womans University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;연구-경력&#34;&gt;연구 경력&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2017 - current : Post Doctoral researcher, Dept. of Atmospheric Sciences, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;수상내역&#34;&gt;수상내역&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;제 1회 기상위성을 활용한 연구성과 경진대회 장려상 (2015년)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;논문&#34;&gt;논문&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lee, Y.-R., D.-B. Shin, J.-H. Kim, and H.-S. Park, 2015: Precipitation estimation over radar gap areas based on satellite and adjacent radar observations, Atmospheric Measurement Techniques, 8, 719-728.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yoo, J.-M., Y.-R. Lee, D. Kim, S.-M. Oh, M.-J. Jeong, W.R. Stockwell, P. K. Kundu, D.-B. Shin, and S.-J. Lee, 2014: New indices for wet scavenging of air pollutants (O3, CO, NO2, SO2, and PM10) by summertime rain, Atmospheric Environment, 82, 226-237.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lee, Y.-R., J.-M. Yoo, M.-J. Jeong, Y.-I. Won, T. Hearty, and D.-B. Shin, 2013: Comparison between MODIS and AIRS/AMSU satellite-derived surface skin temperatures. Atmospheric Measurement Techniques, 6, 445-455.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>김지섭</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/people/jiseobkim/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 01:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/people/jiseobkim/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;연구분야&#34;&gt;연구분야&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Remote sensing&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Atmospheric radiative transfer&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Optical properties&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cloud microphysics&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Rainfall rate retrieval&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;학력&#34;&gt;학력&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ph.d.&lt;/strong&gt; (2023) in Atmospheric Science, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B.Sc&lt;/strong&gt; (2016) in Atmospheric Science, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;수상내역&#34;&gt;수상내역&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(2023.11) 우수학위논문상 (수상기관: 한국기상학회)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(2023.01) 학과 우수논문 장려상 (수상기관: 연세대학교)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(2022.01) 학과 우수논문상 (수상기관: 연세대학교)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(2021.10) 우수논문발표상 (수상기관: 한국기상학회)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(2017.10) 3차원 과학적 가시화 경진대회 대상 (수상기관: 한국과학기술정보연구원)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;논문&#34;&gt;논문&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim J., D.-B. Shin, and D. Kim, 2023: Effects of inhomogeneous ice particle habit distribution on passive microwave radiative transfer simulations, IEEE Trans. Geosci. Remote Sens. (in second revision, conditionally accepted)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim D., D.-B. Shin, J. Kim, M.-J. Kang, H.-K. Lee, and H.-Y. Chun, 2022: Differences in satellite-based latent heating profiles between the 2015/16 disruption and westerly phase of the quasi-biennial oscillation, J. Geophys. Res., 127(19), e2021JD036254.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim J., D.-B. Shin, and D. Kim, 2022: Considering various multimoment bulk microphysics schemes for simulation of passive microwave radiative signatures, IEEE Trans. Geosci. Remote Sens., 60, 1-15.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim J. and D.-B. Shin, 2020: A comparative study of rain/no-rain classification results using PCT from GPM/GMI data by precipitation type, IEEE Trans. Geosci. Remote Sens., 58(12), 8541-8554.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Choi Y., D.-B. Shin, J. Kim, and M. Joh, 2019: Passive microwave precipitation retrieval algorithm with a priori databases of various cloud microphysics schemes: Tropical cyclone applications, IEEE Trans. Geosci. Remote Sens., 58(4), 2366-2382.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>김효정</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/people/hyojeongkim/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 01:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/people/hyojeongkim/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;연구분야&#34;&gt;연구분야&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Climate-carbon cycle interactions&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ocean circulations&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Low-frequency internal variabilities&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Climate modeling&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;학력&#34;&gt;학력&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ph.D&lt;/strong&gt; (2022) in Atmospheric Sciences, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;M.Sc&lt;/strong&gt; (2017) in Atmospheric Sciences, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B.Sc&lt;/strong&gt; (2015) in Atmospheric Sciences, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;수상내역&#34;&gt;수상내역&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(2022.06) Excellent Thesis Award, Yonsei University&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(2021.01) Award for Global Outstanding Student, Hyundai Motor Chung Mong-Koo Foundation&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(2020.02) Outstanding Paper Award, BK21Plus Institute of Earth-Atmosphere-Astronomy&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(2019.07) Award for Global Outstanding Student, Hyundai Motor Chung Mong-Koo Foundation&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;논문&#34;&gt;논문&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;H.-J. Kim, J.-S. Kim, J.-H. Park, and Y.-G. Ham (in preparation) North Tropical Atlantic SST as a Climatic Driver of Wildfire Activity in Brazilian Cerrado.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;H.-J. Kim, J.-S. Kim, S.–I. An, J. Shin, J.-H. Oh, and J.-S. Kug (in preparation) Pervasive Fire Danger Continued Under a Negative Emission Scenario.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;M.-K. Sung, S.-I. An, J. Shin, J.-H. Park, Y.-M. Yang, H.-J. Kim, and M. Chang (2023) Ocean fronts as decadal thermostats modulating continental warming hiatus, Nat Commun, 14, 7777.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;J.-H. Park, J.-S. Kug, Y.-M. Yang, M.-K. Sung, S. Kim, H.-J. Kim, H.-J. Park, and S.-I. An (2023) Distinct decadal modulation of Atlantic-Niño influence on ENSO, npj Clim Atmos Sci 6, 105. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41612-023-00429-9&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41612-023-00429-9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;H.-J. Kim, S.-I. An., J.-H. Park, M.-K. Sung, D. Kim, Y. Choi, and J.-S. Kim (2023) North Atlantic Oscillation impact on the thermohaline circulation shaped by the mean states, npj Clim Atmos Sci 6, 25. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41612-023-00354-x&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41612-023-00354-x&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;J.-H. Park, S.-W. Yeh, J.-S. Kug, Y.-M. Yang, H.-S. Jo, H.-J. Kim, and S.-I. An (2023) Two regimes of inter-basin interactions between the Atlantic and Pacific Oceans on interannual timescales, npj Clim Atmos Sci 6, 13. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41612-023-00332-3&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41612-023-00332-3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;S.-K. Kim, J. Shin, S.-I. An, H.-J. Kim, N. Im, S.-P. Xie, J.-S. Kug, and S.-W. Yeh (2022) Widespread irreversible changes in surface temperature and precipitation to CO2 forcing, Nat Clim Chang 12, 834–840. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41558-022-01452-z&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41558-022-01452-z&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;S.-K. Kim, H.-J. Kim, S.-I. An., and H. Dijkstra (2022) Slow and soft passage through tipping point of the Atlantic Meridional Overturning Circulation in a changing climate, npj Clim Atmos Sci 5, 13. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41612-022-00236-8&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41612-022-00236-8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;S.-I. An, J. Shin, S.-W. Yeh, S.-W. Son, J.-S. Kug, S.-K., Min, and H.-J. Kim (2021) Global cooling hiatus driven by an AMOC overshoot in a carbon dioxide removal scenario, Earth’s Future, 9, e2021EF002165&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;H.-J. Kim, S.-I. An, S.-K. Kim, and J.-H. Park (2021) Feedback processes modulating the sensitivity of Atlantic Thermohaline Circulation to freshwater forcing timescales, J Clim, 34, 5081-5092&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;S.-I. An, H.-J. Kim, and S.-K. Kim (2021) Rate-dependent hysteresis of the Atlantic Meridional Overturning Circulation system and its asymmetric loop, Geophy Res Lett, 48, e2020GL090132&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;H.-J. Kim, S.-I. An, and D. Kim (2021) Timescale-dependent AMOC-AMO relationship in an earth system model of intermediate complexity, Int J Climatol, 41, E3298-E3306&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;H.-J. Kim and S.-I. An (2019) Impact of North Atlantic Freshwater Forcing on Pacific Meridional Overturning Circulation under Glacial and Interglacial Conditions, J Clim, 32. 4641-4659&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;S.-I. An, H.-J. Kim, W. Park, and B. Schneider (2017) Impact of ENSO on East Asian winter monsoon during interglacial periods: effect of orbital forcing. Clim Dyn, 49(9), 3209-3219.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>윤정희</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/people/jungheeyun/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 01:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/people/jungheeyun/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;연구분야&#34;&gt;연구분야&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mesoscale ocean eddies&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Air-Sea interactions&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Coupled Atmosphere-Ocean Dynamics&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;학력&#34;&gt;학력&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ph.D&lt;/strong&gt; (2023) in Atmospheric Sciences, Pusan National University, Busan, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;M.Sc&lt;/strong&gt; (2016) in Atmospheric Sciences, Pusan National University, Busan, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B.Sc&lt;/strong&gt; (2014) in Atmospheric Sciences, Pusan National University, Busan, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;경력&#34;&gt;경력&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(2023.09 - Present) Postdoctoral Researcher, Department of Atmospheric Sciences, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(2016.09 - 2017.02) Research Assistant, Research Center for Climate Science, Pusan National University, Busan, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;수상내역&#34;&gt;수상내역&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(2022) Academic Award, College of Natural Sciences in Pusan National University&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;논문&#34;&gt;논문&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yun, J., Ha, K.-J., and Lee, S.-S. (2024). Impact of greenhouse warming on mesoscale eddy characteristics in high-resolution climate simulations. Environmental Research Letters, 19(1).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, H. R., Moon, M., Yun, J., and Ha, K. J. (2023). Trends and Spatio-Temporal Variability of Summer Mean and Extreme Precipitation across South Korea for 1973-2022. Asia-Pacific Journal of Atmospheric Sciences, 1-14.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yun, J., and Ha, K.-J. (2022). Physical Processes in Sea Fog Formation and Characteristics of Turbulent Air-Sea Fluxes at Socheongcho Ocean Research Station in the Yellow Sea. Frontiers in Marine Science, 9.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ha, K.-J., Nam, S., Jeong, J.-Y., Moon, I.-J., Lee, M., Yun, J., Jang, C. J., Kim, Y. S., Byun, D.-S., Heo, K.-Y., and Shim, J.-S. (2019). Observations Utilizing Korea Ocean Research Stations and their Applications for Process Studies. Bulletin of the American Meteorological Society, 100(10), 2061-2075.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yun, J., Ha, K.-J., and Jo, Y.-H. (2017). Interdecadal changes in winter surface air temperature over East Asia and their possible causes. Climate Dynamics, 51(4), 1375-1390.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yun, J., Oh, H., and Ha, K.-J. (2015) Observation and Analysis of Turbulent Fluxes Observed at Ieodo Ocean Research Station in Autumn 2014. Atmosphere, 25(4), 707-718. (in Korean with English abstract).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>최연주</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/people/yeonjuchoi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 01:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/people/yeonjuchoi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;연구분야&#34;&gt;연구분야&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mesoscale eddy&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ocean Mixed Layer&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Large Eddy Simulation&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Atmospheric Boundary Layer&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;학력&#34;&gt;학력&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ph.D&lt;/strong&gt; (2022) in Atmospheric Sciences, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B.Sc&lt;/strong&gt; (2015) in Atmospheric Sciences, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;수상내역&#34;&gt;수상내역&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(2022.07) Outstanding Young Scientist Award, 12th International Workshop on Modeling the Ocean&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(2020.10) Outstanding Paper Award, Graduate School of Yonsei University&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(2018.05) Young scientist selected for PICES 2018 attendance support, The Korean&#xA;Society of Oceanography&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(2017.07) Outstanding Young Scientist Award, 9th International Workshop on&#xA;Modeling the Ocean&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(2014.03) 3rd place, Computational heat fluid software (EDISON) utilization&#xA;competition, Ministry of Science, ICT and Future Planning, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;논문&#34;&gt;논문&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Y. Choi, Y. Noh, N. Hirose, and H. Song (2022) Improvement of the Ocean Mixed Layer Model via Large Eddy Simulation and Inverse Estimation, J. Atmos. Ocean. Technol. (online published)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;H.-J. Kim, S. -I. An., J.-H. Park, M.-K. Sung, D. Kim, Y. Choi, and J. -S. Kim (2022) North Atlantic Oscillation Impact on the Thermohaline Circulation Shaped by the Mean States, (submitted to NPJ Clim.Atmos. Sci.)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Y. Tak, H. Song, Y. Noh, and Y. Choi (2022) Physical and Biogeochemical Responses in the Southern Ocean to a Simple Parameterization of Langmuir Circulation, (submitted to Ocean Model.)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Y. Choi and Y. Noh (2020) Comparison of the Atmospheric and Oceanic Boundary Layers During Convection and their Latitudinal Dependence, J. Geophys. Res. Oceans&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Noh. Y. and Y. Choi (2018), Comments on “Langmuir Turbulence and Surface Heating in the Ocean Surface Boundary Layer”, J. Phys. Oceanogr., 455-458.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ok. H., Y. Noh, and Y. Choi (2017), Influence of Pycnocline Smoothing and Subgrid-Scale Variability of Density Profiles on the Determination of Mixed Layer Depth, J. Atmos. Oceanic Technol., 34, 2083-2101.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>이재원</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/people/jwlee/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 08:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/people/jwlee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;연구분야&#34;&gt;연구분야&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Atmospheric data analysis with Statistics&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Instruments and Methods of Meteorological Observation&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;학력&#34;&gt;학력&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ph.D.&lt;/strong&gt; (1997) in Atmospheric Sciences, University of Missouri-Columbia, Columbia, Missouri, USA&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;M.Sc&lt;/strong&gt; (1987) in Atmospheric Sciences, Yonsei Unversity, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B.Sc&lt;/strong&gt; (1985) in Atmospheric Sciences, Yonsei Unversity, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;연구경력&#34;&gt;연구경력&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sep.2019 - Dec.2021: Professor, Meteorological Human Resources Development Institute, KMA&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sep.2017 - Sep.2019: Director-General, Aviation Meteorological Office, KMA&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jan.2016 - Sep.2017: Director, National Climate Data Center, KMA&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jul.2014 - Jan.2015: Director-General, National Meteorological Satellite Center, KMA&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;논문&#34;&gt;논문&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kim, H. K., Kang, I. K., Lee, J. W. Lee, Y. S., (2016), A comparison of imputation methods for the consecutive missing temperature data. The Korean Journal of Applied Statistics, 9, 549-557 (in Korean).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hong, J. W., Hong, J. K., Lee, S. E., Lee, J. W., (2013), Spatial Distribution of Urban Heat Island based on Local Climate Zone of Automatic Weather Station in Seoul Metropolitan Area.  Atmosphere, 23, 413-424 (in Korean).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ku, C. Y., Shin, Y. H., Lee, J. W., Kim, H. S., (2012), The Study on the Grid Size Regarding Spatial Interpolation for Local Climate Maps. The Korean Association of Professional Geographers. 46. 489-500 (in Korean).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Byon, J. Y., Choi, Y. J., Lee, J. W., (2011), Global Distribution of Surface Layer Wind Speed for the years 2000-2009 Based on the NCEP Reanalysis. Atmosphere, 21, 439-466 (in Korean).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Choi, Y. E.,  Jeong, J. J., Lee, J. W., Kim, H. S., Roh, K. S., Kim, E. S.., Park, G. I. B, Kim, Y. J., Park, C. Y., (2011), Defining Class Intervals and Color Scheme of Choropleth Maps for the Production of 1981~2010 Korea Climate Atlas. JKCA, 11, 105-112 (in Korean)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>김승기</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/people/kimsoongki/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/people/kimsoongki/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;연구분야&#34;&gt;연구분야&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Nonlinear ENSO Theory &amp;amp; Dynamics&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;AMOC&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;학력&#34;&gt;학력&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ph.D.&lt;/strong&gt; (2023) in Atmospheric Sciences, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;M.Sc&lt;/strong&gt; (2019) in Atmospheric Sciences, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B.Sc&lt;/strong&gt; (2017) in Atmospheric Sciences, Physics, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;수상내역&#34;&gt;수상내역&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;학과우수논문상 (2023)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;논문&#34;&gt;논문&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;S. Paik,  S.-I. An, S.-K. Min, A. D. King, S.-K. Kim (2023) Emergent constraints on future extreme precipitation intensification: From global to continental scales, Weather and Climate Extremes, 42, 100613.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;C. Liu, S.-I. An, F.-F. Jin, M. F. Stuecker, W. Zhang, J.-S. Kug, X. Yuan, J. Shin, A. Xue, X. Geng, S.-K. Kim (2023) ENSO skewness hysteresis and associated changes in strong El Niño under a CO2 removal scenario, npj Climate and Atmospheric Science, 6, 117.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;C. Liu, S.-I. An, F.-F. Jin, J. Shin, J.-S. Kug, W. Zhang, M. F. Stuecker, X. Yuan, A. Xue, X. Geng, S.-K. Kim (2023) Hysteresis of the El Niño-Southern Oscillation to CO2 forcing, Science Advances, 9(31), eadh8442.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;S.-I. An, H.-J. Park, S.-K. Kim, W. Cai, A. Santoso, D. Kim, J.-S. Kug (2023) Main drivers of Indian Ocean Dipole asymmetry revealed by a simple IOD model, npj Climate and Atmospheric Science, 6, 93.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;S. K. Mondal, S.-I. An, S.-K. Min, S.-K. Kim, J. Shin, S. Paik, N. Im, C. Liu (2023) Hysteresis and irreversibility of global extreme precipitation to anthropogenic CO2  emission, Weather and Climate Extremes, 40, 100561.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;R. Olson, S.-K. Kim, Y. Fan, S.-I. An (2022) Probabilistic projections of El Niño Southern Oscillation properties accounting for model dependence and skill, Scientific Reports, 12, 22128.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;S.-K. Kim, J. Shin, S.-I. An, H.-J. Kim, N. Im, S.-P. Xie, J.-S. Kug, S.-W. Yeh (2022) Widespread irreversible changes in surface temperature and precipitation in response to CO2 forcing, Nature Climate Change.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;S.-K. Kim, A. Timmermann, J.-S. Kim, R. Olson, S.-I. An (2022) A low-order dynamical model for fire-vegetation-climate interactions, Environmental Research Letters, 17, 094004.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;S.-I. An, H.-J. Park, S.-K. Kim, J. Shin, S.-W. Yeh, J.-S. Jug (2022) Intensity changes of Indian Ocean Dipole Mode in a Carbon Dioxide Removal Scenario, npj Climate and Atmospheric Science, 5, 20.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;S.-K. Kim, H.-J. Kim, H. A. Dijkstra, S.-I. An (2022) Slow and soft passage through tipping point of the Atlantic Meridional Overturning Circulation in a changing climate, npj Climate and Atmospheric Science, 5, 13.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;R. Olson, S.-I. An, Y. Fan, S.-K. Kim (2021) A flexible data-driven cyclostationary model for probability density of El Niño-Southern Oscillation, Chaos, 31(10), 103126.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;S.-K. Kim, S.-I. An (2021) Seasonal Gap Theory for ENSO Phase Locking, Journal of Climate, 34(14), 5621-5634.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;H.-J. Kim, S.-I. An, S.-K. Kim, J.-H. Park (2021) Feedback Processes Modulating the Sensitivity of Atlantic Thermohaline Circulation to Freshwater Forcing Timescales, Journal of Climate, 34(12), 5081-5091.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;R. Olson, S.-I. An, S.-K. Kim, Y. Fan (2021) A novel approach for discovering stochastic models behind data applied to El Niño–Southern Oscillation, Scientific Reports, 11, 2648.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;S.-I. An, H-.J. Kim, S.-K. Kim (2021) Rate-Dependent Hysteresis of the Atlantic Meridional Overturning Circulation System and Its Asymmetric Loop, Geophysical Research Letters, 48(1), e2020GL090132.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;S.-I. An, S.-K. Kim, A. Timmermann (2020) Fokker–Planck dynamics of the El Niño-Southern Oscillation, Scientific Reports, 10, 16282.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;S.-K. Kim, S.-I. An (2020) Untangling El Niño‐La Niña Asymmetries Using a Nonlinear Coupled Dynamic Index, Geophysical Research Letters, 47(4), e2019GL085881.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>오동건</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/people/donggunoh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/people/donggunoh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;연구분야&#34;&gt;연구분야&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Large-eddy simulation&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cloud microphysics parameterization&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Particle-based cloud model&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Turbulence&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;학력&#34;&gt;학력&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ph.D.&lt;/strong&gt; (2023) in Atmospheric Sciences, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B.Sc&lt;/strong&gt; (2015) in Atmospheric Sciences, Yonsei University, Seoul, Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;수상내역&#34;&gt;수상내역&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(2023) Outstanding Presentation Award, American Meteorological Society&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;논문&#34;&gt;논문&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;D. Oh, Y. Noh and F. Hoffmann (2023) Paths from Aerosol Particles to Activation and Cloud Droplets in Shallow Cumulus Clouds: The Roles of Entrainment and Supersaturation Fluctuation, J. Geophy. Res. Atmos (In revision)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;D. Oh and Y. Noh (2022) Roles of Drop Size Distribution and Turbulence in Autoconversion Based on Lagrangian Cloud Model Simulations, J. Geophy. Res. Atmos, 127(16), e2022JD036495.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Noh, Y., D. Oh, F. Hoffmann, and S. Raasch, &amp;ldquo;A Cloud Microphysics Parameterization for Shallow Cumulus Clouds Based on Lagrangian Cloud Model Simulations&amp;rdquo;, J. Atmos. Sci., 75, 4031-4047, 2018.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>송병권</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/people/bgsong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 01:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/people/bgsong/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;연구분야&#34;&gt;연구분야&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The dynamics of the mesosphere and lower thermosphere (MLT)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Atmospheric waves including planetary waves, gravity waves, and atmospheric tides&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Global whole atmosphere model simulations&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;학력&#34;&gt;학력&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ph.D.&lt;/strong&gt; (2023) in Atmospheric Sciences, Yonsei University, Seoul, South Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B.Sc&lt;/strong&gt; (2014) in Atmospheric Sciences, Yonsei University, Seoul, South Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;경력&#34;&gt;경력&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mar. 2023 - Present: Mathematical Atmospheric Physics Laboratory (MAPL), Department of Atmospheric Sciences, Yonsei University&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dec. 2018 - Dec. 2021: Division of Atmospheric Sciences, Korea Polar Research Institute (KOPRI)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;논문&#34;&gt;논문&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Song, B.‐G.&lt;/strong&gt;, &amp;amp; Song, I.‐S. (2024). Coupling of long-term trends of zonal winds between the mesopause and stratosphere in southern winter. Geophysical Research Letters. 51, e2023GL107014. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2023GL107014&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2023GL107014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Song, B.‐G.&lt;/strong&gt;, Chun, H.‐Y., Song, I.‐S., Lee, C., Kim, J.-H., &amp;amp; Jee, G. (2023). Long-term characteristics of the meteor radar winds observed at King Sejong Station, Antarctica. Journal of Geophysical Research: Atmospheres. 128, e2022JD037190. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2022JD037190&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2022JD037190&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Song, B.‐G.&lt;/strong&gt;, Song, I. ‐S., Chun, H. ‐Y., Lee, C., Kam, H., Kim, Y. H., Kang, M. ‐J., Hindley, N. P., &amp;amp; Mitchell, N. J. (2021). Activities of small‐scale gravity waves in the upper mesosphere observed from meteor radar at King Sejong Station, Antarctica (62.22°S, 58.78°W) and their potential sources. Journal of Geophysical Research: Atmospheres, 126(10), e2021JD034528. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2021jd034528&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2021jd034528&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Song, B.‐G.&lt;/strong&gt;, Chun, H.-Y., &amp;amp; Song, I.-S. (2020). Role of gravity waves in a vortex-split sudden stratospheric warming in January 2009. Journal of the Atmospheric Sciences, 77(10), 3321–3342. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1175/JAS-D-20-0039.1&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1175/JAS-D-20-0039.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
